<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<testrepo>
  <chapter num="1">
    <question>
      <q>Which statement best characterizes an organization?</q>
      <a>It is a goal-directed entity that has members who set goals and achieve them through strategic planning.</a>
      <b>It is an entity with identifiable permanent boundaries.</b>
      <c>It is goal-directed social entity that has a deliberately structured activity system and a permeable boundary</c>
      <d>It is a business that performs work activities and contributes to its society by employing people</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is the key element that makes an organization an organization and not just a group of individuals?</q>
      <a>buildings and policies</a>
      <b>people and their relationships</b>
      <c>profits</c>
      <d>facilities location</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Managers of nonprofit organizations deal with many diverse stakeholders. Who must they market their services to in addition to donors and clients?</q>
      <a>shareholders</a>
      <b>volunteers</b>
      <c>charitable organizations</c>
      <d>employees</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>According to the textbook, why are organizations important to society?</q>
      <a>They create value for owners, customers, and employees.</a>
      <b>They establish important relationships with the government.</b>
      <c>They reduce transactions costs.</c>
      <d>They divide the resources needed for achieving desired goals and outcomes.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>According to the textbook, why do organizations exist?</q>
      <a>to bring in a profit</a>
      <b>to develop advanced manufacturing and information technologies</b>
      <c>to challenge diversity, ethics, and the motivation and coordination of employees</c>
      <d>to facilitate innovation</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following goals drives organizations?</q>
      <a>profitability</a>
      <b>maintaining organizational stability</b>
      <c>innovation</c>
      <d>developing change</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which statement best describes an open system?</q>
      <a>Outputs are continuously reused in a sustainable cycle of production and consumption.</a>
      <b>Inputs are received from the environment, transformed and then returned to the environment.</b>
      <c>All the energy it needs is contained within itself.</c>
      <d>Products and services are used to make inputs.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which statement provides the best generic description of what an organization does?</q>
      <a>It acquires inputs from the environment, transforms them, and discharges outputs back to the environment.</a>
      <b>It operates its transformation processes independently from its environment.</b>
      <c>It attempts to shield its transformation processes from the environment.</c>
      <d>It focuses on the efficiency of its input acquisition and its transformation processes.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>From which of the following sources do nonprofit organizations usually get their resources?</q>
      <a>government grants</a>
      <b>selling shares</b>
      <c>investment income</c>
      <d>selling goods and services</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is characteristic of an open system and its subsystem?</q>
      <a>a transformation process that involves production, maintenance, adaptation, and management</a>
      <b>an input selection known for being so accurate that it can be closed</b>
      <c>subjective output criteria</c>
      <d>boundary spanners connect employees to products and to organizational subsystems</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which subsystem would the surgery department in a hospital belong to?</q>
      <a>production</a>
      <b>boundary spanning</b>
      <c>maintenance</c>
      <d>management</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a component of organizational subsystems?</q>
      <a>boundary subsystems responsible for exchanges with the external environment</a>
      <b>maintenance subsystems responsible for keeping production facilities in operating order</b>
      <c>human subsystems that serve as employees</c>
      <d>technical subsystems that become the basis for information processing</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What does the term technical core refer to?</q>
      <a>computer hardware that runs information processing in the organization</a>
      <b>people who do the basic work of the organization, producing product and service outputs</b>
      <c>administrators who run the organization</c>
      <d>top management who have been promoted from within and thereby know the inner core of organizational processes</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which one of Mintzbergs basic parts of an organization deals with functions such as human resources, organizational development, the employee cafeteria, and maintenance staff?</q>
      <a>technical support</a>
      <b>human infrastructure</b>
      <c>administrative support</c>
      <d>top management</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is one of Mintzbergs five basic parts of an organization?</q>
      <a>administrative core</a>
      <b>computer infrastructure</b>
      <c>top management support</c>
      <d>middle management</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is the subsystem responsible for directing and coordinating other parts of the organization?</q>
      <a>the technical core</a>
      <b>management</b>
      <c>human resources</c>
      <d>accounting</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following provides a description of the internal characteristics of an organization?</q>
      <a>contextual dimensions</a>
      <b>contingency analysis</b>
      <c>organizational dynamics</c>
      <d>structural dimensions</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following structural dimensions is best represented by the 385-page book McDonalds uses to describe all rules and procedures in each of its stores?</q>
      <a>learning theory</a>
      <b>sequential interdependence</b>
      <c>formalization</c>
      <d>specialization</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is one of the elements of organizational design?</q>
      <a>culture</a>
      <b>management</b>
      <c>structure</c>
      <d>technology</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term refers to the degree to which organizational tasks are subdivided into separate jobs?</q>
      <a>formalization</a>
      <b>specialization</b>
      <c>professionalism</c>
      <d>centralization</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following refer(s) to the deployment of people to various functions and departments?</q>
      <a>professionalization</a>
      <b>specialization</b>
      <c>personnel ratios</c>
      <d>hierarchy of authority</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which statement best describes contextual and structural dimensions?</q>
      <a>They represent only the external environment.</a>
      <b>They are centralization and personnel ratios.</b>
      <c>They represent only the organizational characteristics.</c>
      <d>They provide a basis for the measurement and analysis of characteristics that cannot be seen by the casual observer.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following refers to how the organization actually produces the products and services it provides for customers and includes flexible manufacturing, advanced information systems, and the Internet?</q>
      <a>size of the organization</a>
      <b>organizational technology</b>
      <c>organizational goals</c>
      <d>organizational culture</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a contextual, rather than a structural, dimension of an organization?</q>
      <a>labour force</a>
      <b>culture</b>
      <c>professionalism</c>
      <d>centralization</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is demonstrated in the comparison of EllisDon and Tim Hortons in the textbooks In Practice activity?</q>
      <a>Larger organizations need to have tight controls at the top.</a>
      <b>Successful organizations can have very different strategies and goal emphases.</b>
      <c>A moderate to high level of formalization is crucial to an organizations success.</c>
      <d>Centralization is necessary in organizations when they face high levels of competition.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following describes the degree to which an organization achieves its goals?</q>
      <a>effectiveness</a>
      <b>efficiency</b>
      <c>organizational strategy</c>
      <d>stakeholder profitability</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following integrates diverse organizational activities by looking at various constituents and what they want from the organization?</q>
      <a>contextual dimensions</a>
      <b>organizational culture</b>
      <c>efficiency</c>
      <d>stakeholder approach</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What did scientific management, pioneered by Frederick Taylor, claim decisions about organizations and job design should be based on?</q>
      <a>scientific procedures after careful study of individual situations</a>
      <b>insights of practitioners</b>
      <c>leadership, motivation, and human resource management</c>
      <d>management theory</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which statement best characterizes scientific management?</q>
      <a>It used scientifically tested methods of motivation to improve organizational performance.</a>
      <b>It is an outgrowth of the Hawthorne studies, which found that people performed best in an environment of clearly specified, narrow job task.</b>
      <c>It focuses on effectiveness rather than efficiency.</c>
      <d>It is successful at increasing output, in part through the use of incentive systems.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following emphasize designing and managing organizations on an impersonal, rational basis through such elements as clearly defined authority and responsibility, formal record keeping, and uniform application of standard rules?</q>
      <a>administrative principles</a>
      <b>scientific management</b>
      <c>bureaucracy</c>
      <d>hierarchy</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Interpretations of which of the following concluded that positive treatment of employees improved their motivation and productivity?</q>
      <a>administrative principles</a>
      <b>stakeholder approaches</b>
      <c>scientific management</c>
      <d>the Hawthorne studies</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>In todays world, which of the following do savvy managers recognize?</q>
      <a>They cannot measure, predict, or control their environment.</a>
      <b>Centralized structures help them cope with organizational demands.</b>
      <c>They do the thought work while employees perform the labour.</c>
      <d>Leadership is based on thoroughness of written documents.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>According to the textbook, what does the term contingency refer to?</q>
      <a>Organizations should be structured loosely.</a>
      <b>Management structure is determined by the era or times.</b>
      <c>One thing depends on other things, such as structure depending on environment.</c>
      <d>Designing and managing organizations on an impersonal, rational basis.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>John Black, a management consultant, successfully implemented an MBO program on his first consulting job. He now recommends MBO to all his clients. In so doing, what aspect of organizational design would the textbook say he is ignoring?</q>
      <a>the latest techniques for solving problems</a>
      <b>the principles of contingency theory</b>
      <c>the external environment of the organization</c>
      <d>the internal environment of the organization</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which statement best describes the learning organization?</q>
      <a>They place high value on problem solving.</a>
      <b>They emphasize training as the essential value.</b>
      <c>They engage people in sessions focused on finding maximum organizational efficiency.</c>
      <d>They facilitate better decision-making when the environment is unstable.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>In a learning organization, what is used to encourage openness, equality, continuous improvement, and change?</q>
      <a>empowerment</a>
      <b>the culture</b>
      <c>strategy</c>
      <d>the structure</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which statement best describes organizational behaviour?</q>
      <a>It is a micro approach to organizations, focusing on individuals</a>
      <b>It focuses on the whole organization as a unit of analysis</b>
      <c>It is an umbrella that encompasses the study of organizational theory.</c>
      <d>It is a subset of organizational theory.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which statement best describes organizational behaviour?</q>
      <a>It is the same as the study of organizational theory.</a>
      <b>It is a macro analysis of the whole organization.</b>
      <c>It is focused on people, structure, and environment.</c>
      <d>It is a micro approach focusing on the individual.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>At what level is the primary level of analysis in organizational theory done?</q>
      <a>environmental</a>
      <b>organizational</b>
      <c>departmental</c>
      <d>individual</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
  </chapter>
  <chapter num="2">
    <question>
      <q>The chief of one police force emphasizes the number of arrests while another police chief emphasizes community outreach. Which effectiveness value is the second police chief most likely using?</q>
      <a>human relations</a>
      <b>open-systems</b>
      <c>rational-goal</c>
      <d>internal-process</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Top managers have a number of roles in the achievement of organizational effectiveness. Which of the following is included in an examination of the internal environment?</q>
      <a>opportunities</a>
      <b>weaknesses</b>
      <c>uncertainty</c>
      <d>resource availability</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Top managers have a number of roles in achieving organizational effectiveness. Which of the following is included in an examination of the external environment?</q>
      <a>threats</a>
      <b>mission</b>
      <c>production technology</c>
      <d>strengths</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What do the choices top managers make about goals, strategies, and organizational design have a tremendous impact on?</q>
      <a>organizational profitability</a>
      <b>organizational efficiency</b>
      <c>organizational effectiveness</c>
      <d>organizational market share</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is top management doing when looking for strengths and weaknesses?</q>
      <a>assessing the external environment</a>
      <b>analyzing the competition</b>
      <c>evaluating the internal situation in order to define its distinctive competence</c>
      <d>determining the effectiveness of operational outcomes</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is the primary responsibility of top management?</q>
      <a>to perform the organizations SWOT analysis</a>
      <b>to determine goals, strategy, and design, in adaptation to the environment</b>
      <c>to set a motivating culture for all employees</c>
      <d>to formalize and centralize the firm</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What most commonly occurs when setting goals and selecting a strategy?</q>
      <a>The environment is ignored but the organizations strengths and weaknesses are evaluated to determine the appropriate goals and strategy.</a>
      <b>Goals are set so high that they can rarely be attained.</b>
      <c>New goals and strategies are chosen on the basis of environmental needs and the organization is redesigned accordingly.</c>
      <d>Environment and current structure and goals are considered simultaneously.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is another term for mission?</q>
      <a>operative goals</a>
      <b>decision guidelines</b>
      <c>official goals</c>
      <d>performance standards</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>When Google states its official goal is to not be evil, what does this provide them with in the eyes of stakeholders?</q>
      <a>measurable objectives</a>
      <b>legitimacy</b>
      <c>employee direction</c>
      <d>decision guidelines</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following represents the best way to measure the overall performance of for-profit organizations?</q>
      <a>efficiency</a>
      <b>earnings per share</b>
      <c>innovation</c>
      <d>productivity</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Mini-Markets wants to capture 25% of the convenience market business in PEI. What type of goal is illustrated by this example?</q>
      <a>official</a>
      <b>operative</b>
      <c>generic</c>
      <d>legitimacy</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following includes the training, promotion, safety, and individual personal growth?</q>
      <a>market share</a>
      <b>innovation</b>
      <c>productivity of the industry</c>
      <d>employee development</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What kind of carefully balanced goals do successful organizations use?</q>
      <a>operative</a>
      <b>innovation</b>
      <c>visionary</c>
      <d>generic</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is traditionally defined as the extent to which goals are obtained in the organization?</q>
      <a>efficiency</a>
      <b>scientific management</b>
      <c>strategy</c>
      <d>effectiveness</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term refers to a plan for interacting with the competitive environment to achieve organizational goals?</q>
      <a>strategy</a>
      <b>design</b>
      <c>culture</c>
      <d>structure</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following are models for formulating organizational strategies?</q>
      <a>Perrows typology and Porters model</a>
      <b>Perrows typology and Pfeiffers typology</b>
      <c>Porters model and Miles and Snows typology</c>
      <d>Pfeiffers typology and Miles and Snows model</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following researchers work refers to the differentiation strategy?</q>
      <a>Frederic Taylors scientific management.</a>
      <b>Henri Fayols Hawthorne Studies.</b>
      <c>Michael Porters competitive strategies.</c>
      <d>K. D. Bowermans Strategy for Empowerment.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What kind of strategy can reduce rivalry with competitors and fight off the threat of substitute products because customers are loyal to the companys brand?</q>
      <a>low-cost leadership</a>
      <b>focused</b>
      <c>defensive</c>
      <d>differentiation</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following best explains Porters differentiation strategy?</q>
      <a>Differentiation strategies address whether the market scope is broad or narrow.</a>
      <b>Differentiation can be broken down into low-cost or broad-scope categories.</b>
      <c>An airline using the differentiation strategy would be likely to offer travellers refreshments at a reasonable price rather than serve free meals.</c>
      <d>The statement by Starbuckss international president that Were not in the business of filling bellies, were in the business of filling souls is indicative of a differentiation strategy.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What kind of strategy is concerned primarily with stability rather than taking risks or seeking new opportunities for innovation and growth?</q>
      <a>focused</a>
      <b>low-cost leadership</b>
      <c>differentiation</c>
      <d>intensive</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following strategies is exemplified by the slogan Were a no-frills business! When we save, you save!?</q>
      <a>low-cost leadership</a>
      <b>differentiation</b>
      <c>focus</c>
      <d>legitimacy</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which statement best describes the focus strategy?</q>
      <a>It is known for its creative flair.</a>
      <b>It utilizes strong central authority.</b>
      <c>It involves detailed control reports for targeting areas of emphasis.</c>
      <d>It concentrates on a specific regional market or buyer group.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following best describes the prospector strategy in Miles and Snows typology?</q>
      <a>It attempts to maintain a stable business environment by finding a middle ground between stability and innovation.</a>
      <b>It most closely resembles Porters low-cost leadership strategy.</b>
      <c>It responds to environmental threats in an ad hoc fashion without revealing a clear strategy.</c>
      <d>It seeks innovation or risk taking and is therefore best suited to the dynamic environment.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following notions is Miles and Snows strategy typology based on?</q>
      <a>Strategy should correspond to technology.</a>
      <b>Strategy should be congruent with external environment.</b>
      <c>Strategy should be based on human resource capability.</c>
      <d>Strategy should be a fit to the economic resource base.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What kind of strategy tries to maintain a stable business while innovating on the periphery?</q>
      <a>reactor</a>
      <b>prospector</b>
      <c>analyzer</c>
      <d>defender</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which strategy type from Miles and Snows typology best matches with a strong capability in research, a decentralized structure, and an emphasis on flexibility?</q>
      <a>reactor</a>
      <b>low-cost leadership</b>
      <c>prospector</c>
      <d>analyzer</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following need(s) to support a firms competitive approach?</q>
      <a>its financial standings</a>
      <b>its organizational design characteristics</b>
      <c>its informal communication channels</c>
      <d>its environment for green movement</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What does the resource-based approach emphasize?</q>
      <a>input into an organization</a>
      <b>output of an organization</b>
      <c>achievement of profitability</c>
      <d>amount of inventory left idle by the organization</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a strength of the internal process approach?</q>
      <a>It tells management how well the internal processes mesh with the external environment.</a>
      <b>It considers human resources and employee-oriented processes.</b>
      <c>It emphasizes inputs into the organization.</c>
      <d>It emphasizes outputs of the organization.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>If one is measuring work climate, group loyalty, and workermanagement communication as an indication of effectiveness, what approach is most likely being used?</q>
      <a>internal process</a>
      <b>strategic human resources</b>
      <c>quality control</c>
      <d>stakeholder approach</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a contingency approach to the measurement of organizational effectiveness?</q>
      <a>whether the organizations internal activities and processes are efficient</a>
      <b>the system resource approach, which examines product and service outputs</b>
      <c>stakeholders views on effectiveness</c>
      <d>which competing values are applicable</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What kind of approach to organizational effectiveness is concerned with the output side and whether the organization achieves effectiveness in terms of desired levels of output?</q>
      <a>goal</a>
      <b>resource-based</b>
      <c>analytical</c>
      <d>internal process</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>When using the goal approach to effectiveness evaluation, what kind of goals is it best to use?</q>
      <a>operational</a>
      <b>official</b>
      <c>low-level</c>
      <d>nonmeasurable</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following best describes the goal approach to measuring effectiveness?</q>
      <a>Full assessment of effectiveness should consider several goals simultaneously because high achievement on one goal may mean low achievement on another.</a>
      <b>Priority setting requires that only one goal at a time can be achieved.</b>
      <c>Examine the beginning of a process and evaluate if the organization effectively gains its needed resources.</c>
      <d>Assess the organizations activities and assess effectiveness based on efficiencies.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which competing-values approach provides management with structural control and an external focus?</q>
      <a>open-systems emphasis</a>
      <b>rational-goal emphasis</b>
      <c>internal-process emphasis</c>
      <d>human relations emphasis</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which two dimensions (i.e., axes) are the competing-values approach to effectiveness based on?</q>
      <a>open/closed system and values/beliefs of managers</a>
      <b>internal/external focus and flexible/structured control</b>
      <c>high/low analyzability and high/low variety</c>
      <d>environmental change and environmental complexity</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>The Stevens Corporation has goals that reflect deeply rooted values of growth and resource acquisition. In the competing-values approach to effectiveness evaluation, primarily which quadrant would the company be considered to be in?</q>
      <a>rational-goal emphasis</a>
      <b>internal-process emphasis</b>
      <c>open-systems emphasis</c>
      <d>human relations emphasis</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the competing-values approaches to effectiveness evaluation would be used by a firm whose goals revolve around employee training, empowerment and autonomy?</q>
      <a>human relations emphasis</a>
      <b>rational-goal emphasis</b>
      <c>open-systems emphasis</c>
      <d>internal-process emphasis</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following best describes the big questions that strategy researchers are looking at today?</q>
      <a>Which organizational types are best suited for different organizational strategies?</a>
      <b>What are the effects of different organizational strategies on sociopolitical institutions?</b>
      <c>How do organizations change and function in our society and around the world?</c>
      <d>Why do particular industries follow particular strategies?</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
  </chapter>
  <chapter num="3">
    <question>
      <q>What element of organizational structure deals with the pattern of interactions among employees?</q>
      <a>the design of systems to ensure effective communication, coordination, and integration of effort across each position</a>
      <b>the identification of the tasks and processes for each position within the organization</b>
      <c>the grouping together of individuals into departments and of departments into the total organization</c>
      <d>designating formal reporting relationships, including the number of levels in the hierarchy and the span of control of managers and supervisors</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What would a researcher in organizational structure say is important about managing information in an organization?</q>
      <a>Information should flow horizontally, but not vertically.</a>
      <b>Information should flow vertically, but not horizontally.</b>
      <c>The structure should fit the information requirements of the organization.</c>
      <d>It is not possible to give people too much information.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following are used to coordinate activities between the top and bottom of an organization and are designed primarily for control of the organization?</q>
      <a>horizontal linkages</a>
      <b>functional groupings</b>
      <c>vertical linkages</c>
      <d>divisional groupings</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is being used when problems and decisions are funnelled to top levels of the hierarchy for resolution?</q>
      <a>centralized decision making</a>
      <b>functional structure</b>
      <c>horizontal linkage</c>
      <d>full-time integration</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What structural device includes periodic reports, written information, and computer-based communications distributed to managers?</q>
      <a>rules and plans</a>
      <b>hierarchical referral</b>
      <c>vertical information systems</c>
      <d>task forces</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What horizontal linkage mechanism includes a liaison person who communicates and coordinates activities between other departments?</q>
      <a>direct contact</a>
      <b>task forces</b>
      <c>information systems</c>
      <d>teams</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Why would an organizational structure researcher say horizontal linkage mechanisms are important to an organization?</q>
      <a>They cause employees to feel a lack of unity of command.</a>
      <b>They coordinate functional areas when added to a divisional structure.</b>
      <c>They confuse vertical linkages.</c>
      <d>They enable people in different functional departments to exchange information.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>When does a liaison role exist?</q>
      <a>when there is direct contact between managers affected by a problem</a>
      <b>when there is an exchange of paperwork about a problem</b>
      <c>when a temporary committee composed of representatives from each department affected by a problem is formed</c>
      <d>when a person located in one department is required to communicate and coordinate other departments</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Define the role of a full-time integrator ?</q>
      <a>He or she improves vertical linkage of the organization.</a>
      <b>He or she is responsible for the entire project and is located outside of any one department.</b>
      <c>He or she reports to one of the functional departments being coordinated.</c>
      <d>He or she has the responsibility of coordinating only one department.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following would best be linked with full-time integrator?</q>
      <a>brand manager</a>
      <b>task force</b>
      <c>direct contact</c>
      <d>vertical control</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is made up of organizationally or geographically dispersed members who are linked primarily through advanced information and communications technologies?</q>
      <a>virtual teams</a>
      <b>task forces</b>
      <c>full-time integrators</c>
      <d>information systems</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Refer to Organizational Chart 3.1.Which of the following can we accurately conclude from Organizational Chart 3.1?</q>
      <a>There should be no assistant manager.</a>
      <b>The company has a functional structure.</b>
      <c>The company has a divisional structure.</c>
      <d>The general manager has a span of control of five.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Refer to Organizational Chart 3.1.What are some of the strengths of the structure shown in Organizational Chart 3.1?</q>
      <a>clear and simple product responsibility</a>
      <b>The hierarchy makes activity cost determination straightforward</b>
      <c>suitability for an unstable environment</c>
      <d>economies of scale</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Refer to Organizational Chart 3.1.From the perspective of an organizational structure analyst, what is the best assessment of the structure shown in Organizational Chart 3.1?</q>
      <a>It could have a weakness of slow response to environmental changes that require coordination across functional areas.</a>
      <b>It should be changed immediately to a horizontal grouping if the company is growing.</b>
      <c>It would have increased the span of control for the general manager when the assistant manager position was added.</c>
      <d>It has caused high levels of bureaucracy.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Refer to Organizational Chart 3.2. From the perspective of an organizational structure analyst, what is the best assessment of the structure shown in Organizational Chart 3.2?</q>
      <a>To lower fixed costs, this organization should change to a divisional structure with customer account executives heading each major division.</a>
      <b>To improve the communications flow, it is recommended that this company add a full-time integrator between each account executive and operations head.</b>
      <c>The customer account executives can be considered to be integrators.</c>
      <d>The organization does not take advantage of economies of scale within the operations department.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Refer to Organizational Chart 3.2. Which of the following is the best assessment of this organizational structure?</q>
      <a>If well managed, it achieves coordination both within and between customer accounts.</a>
      <b>Efficiency and economy of scale are gained in the functional operations departments.</b>
      <c>It facilitates in-depth artistic and technical competence in operations.</c>
      <d>Balanced joint formal authority between functional and customer account heads ensures decisions not being bumped up to the president.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Refer to Organizational Chart 3.2. Which of the following best describes the structure of this organization?</q>
      <a>The structure is divisional.</a>
      <b>There is duplication of activities between the customer accounts and marketing departments.</b>
      <c>The structure is primarily functional.</c>
      <d>Hierarchical referral is the best means for coordination in this organization.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Chantal Roy is the vice president of marketing for her company. Other officers in the company include the vice presidents of engineering, production, finance, and human resource management. What type of structure does this small company have?</q>
      <a>product</a>
      <b>matrix</b>
      <c>functional</c>
      <d>hybrid</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a characteristic of an organization with a functional structure?</q>
      <a>It reacts quickly to environmental changes.</a>
      <b>It diminishes economies of scale compared to the divisional structure.</b>
      <c>It often results in hierarchy overload.</c>
      <d>It cannot work in small organizations.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>If a company wishes to maintain its basic functional structure, but is having difficulty coordinating across departments because of growth, what should it do?</q>
      <a>It should install horizontal linkages.</a>
      <b>It should realize that the functional structure cannot work and replace it with a matrix structure.</b>
      <c>It may find it necessary to abolish liaison roles.</c>
      <d>It can profit most by adding more functional departments.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is likely to be the result if a domestic company that manufactures four different types of products changes from a functional structure to a divisional structure?</q>
      <a>lower fixed costs</a>
      <b>better coordination within a product area between different functional areas</b>
      <c>more technical development within functional areas</c>
      <d>more centralized decision making</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is one of the benefits of a product or divisional structure?</q>
      <a>It is best suited to fast change in an unstable environment.</a>
      <b>It centralizes decision making.</b>
      <c>It facilitates integration and standardization across product lines.</c>
      <d>It allows units to adapt to differences in products, regions, and clients.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is one of the benefits of a matrix structure?</q>
      <a>It maintains dual-authority relationships.</a>
      <b>It is most effective in an unstable environment.</b>
      <c>It is designed for use within a bureaucracy.</c>
      <d>It is known for its quality of centralization of key decisions for organizational control.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>The matrix structure is the correct structure when three conditions are met. Which of the following is one of these three conditions?</q>
      <a>Pressure exists to share scarce resources across product lines.</a>
      <b>Technical quality is not very important.</b>
      <c>The environmental domain of the organization is simple.</c>
      <d>The environmental domain of the organization is certain and stable.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>In what type of matrix structure do the project/product managers have primary authority, and functional managers take on a more advisory role?</q>
      <a>functional</a>
      <b>virtual</b>
      <c>divisional</c>
      <d>product</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is one of the benefits of the horizontal structure?</q>
      <a>The process owner is responsible for coordinating the core process in its entirety.</a>
      <b>Because team members become recognized experts in a single area, less cross-training that characterizes other organizational forms is needed</b>
      <c>Boundaries between departments are clearly defined to ensure functional expertise.</c>
      <d>The horizontal structure is easy to implement, even if the organization has been rooted in a strict vertical, hierarchical structure.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a key aspect of an organization whose employees are assigned to core processes along a horizontal structure?</q>
      <a>Self-directed teams as the basis of the organizational design and performance.</a>
      <b>The dual-authority structure facilitates communication and coordination.</b>
      <c>The culture is closed, untrustworthy, non-collaborative, and focused on individual accomplishments.</c>
      <d>The structure is grouped based on organizational outputs.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is a potential weakness of the horizontal structure?</q>
      <a>It is inflexible and slow to respond to rapid changes in customer needs.</a>
      <b>Determining core processes to organize around is often difficult.</b>
      <c>There is a failure to promote teamwork.</c>
      <d>Organizational goals are not well understood by employees.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What two things does each of the two types of hybrid structures that are common today combine?</q>
      <a>product and matrix structures; product and horizontal structures</a>
      <b>functional and divisional structures; functional and horizontal structures</b>
      <c>marketing and sales; marketing and logistics</c>
      <d>horizontal and teams; vertical and authority</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>If an organization has too much conflict or if decision making is delayed, what might these problems be a symptom of?</q>
      <a>bureaucracy</a>
      <b>structural alignment</b>
      <c>structural deficiency</c>
      <d>lack of employee motivation</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
  </chapter>
  <chapter num="4">
    <question>
      <q>What is an organizations domain?</q>
      <a>the set of positions and departments within the organization</a>
      <b>the buildings and grounds that are owned or leased by the organization in which inputs are transformed into outputs</b>
      <c>the organizations niche that has been staked out for its products, services, and markets served</c>
      <d>the technical core that is buffered by other departments so that it can operate as a closed system</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What term is used for sectors of the environment that have direct impact on the organization?</q>
      <a>task environment</a>
      <b>general environment</b>
      <c>environmental buffers</c>
      <d>environmental boundary-spanners</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is the task environment?</q>
      <a>all elements that exist outside the organizational boundary</a>
      <b>sectors with which the organization interacts directly</b>
      <c>the domain</c>
      <d>all jobs and positions inherent within the organizational activity</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which sector in an organizations environment relates to understanding consumer preferences?</q>
      <a>industry sector</a>
      <b>international sector</b>
      <c>sociocultural sector</c>
      <d>market sector</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following examples best illustrates how various sectors can have an impact on organizations?</q>
      <a>In the industry sector, labour unions are a significant force.</a>
      <b>In the market sector, an increasing number of foreign-owned manufacturing plants are built in North America.</b>
      <c>In the raw materials sector, steelmakers owned the beverage can market until the mid-1980s.</c>
      <d>In the human resources sector, brand names are fighting it out with lower-cost store brands.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following includes those sectors that might not have a direct impact on the daily operations of a firm but will indirectly influence it?</q>
      <a>the general environment</a>
      <b>the international context</b>
      <c>the task environment</c>
      <d>the buffering roles</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which aspect of the general environment affects an organization due to rapid changes and innovations?</q>
      <a>financial resources</a>
      <b>technology sector</b>
      <c>economic conditions</c>
      <d>the government sector</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Assessment of environmental uncertainty of an organization is based primarily on analysis of which two of the following dimensions?</q>
      <a>the need for information about the environment and the need for resources from the environment</a>
      <b>the number of sectors and the organizations niche</b>
      <c>the extent of turbulence and the amount of available resources</c>
      <d>differentiation and integration</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a dimension of the framework for assessing environmental uncertainty?</q>
      <a>dispersion-contiguity</a>
      <b>simple-complex</b>
      <c>certain-uncertain</c>
      <d>internal-external</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a dimension of the framework for assessing environmental uncertainty?</q>
      <a>stable-unstable</a>
      <b>loose-tight</b>
      <c>known-unknown</c>
      <d>high competitivenesslow competitiveness</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>When Johnson and Johnson had to cope with the Tylenol poisoning issue, which dimension of its environment was most affected?</q>
      <a>simple</a>
      <b>complex</b>
      <c>stable</c>
      <d>unstable</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Often, decision makers do NOT have sufficient information about environmental factors so they have a difficult time predicting external change. What is this called?</q>
      <a>cooptation</a>
      <b>differentiation</b>
      <c>uncertainty</c>
      <d>integration</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>In which of the following types of industries would organizations face the greatest amount of environmental uncertainty? Evaluate</q>
      <a>beer distributors because of simplicity</a>
      <b>universities because of complexity</b>
      <c>airlines because of instability</c>
      <d>appliance manufacturers because of complexity</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What do trend-setting toy companies or high-fashion clothing manufacturers have in common?</q>
      <a>an environment that is stable but complex, therefore requiring a mechanistic structure</a>
      <b>an organic structure, from which we can reason that the environment is highly uncertain</b>
      <c>a large number of dissimilar external elements, which remain about the same over time</c>
      <d>an environment that is simple but unstable, creating relatively high uncertainty</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is the best application of the framework for assessing environmental uncertainty?</q>
      <a>Soft drink bottlers are examples of typical firms in the simple and unstable quadrant.</a>
      <b>Universities are examples of organizations typically found in the complex and stable quadrant.</b>
      <c>Electronic firms are typically found in the simple and stable quadrant.</c>
      <d>Fashion clothing or toy manufacturers would exemplify the complex and unstable quadrant.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is the function of boundary-spanning roles?</q>
      <a>They primarily link data to information.</a>
      <b>They buffer the manufacturing department from outside intrusion that would interfere with efficiency.</b>
      <c>They bring information about environmental changes into the organization.</c>
      <d>They move the firm to internationalism.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Bobby Barista is a researcher in the R and D department at 3M. Part of her job is to read technical and scientific journals, and to attend conferences to find out what new developments are occurring. What sort of role is she carrying out in this part of her job?</q>
      <a>buffering</a>
      <b>maintenance</b>
      <c>boundary spanning</c>
      <d>managerial</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What results from allowing customers in an auto dealership service department to talk directly to the mechanic rather than to a service manager?</q>
      <a>It creates a buffering role.</a>
      <b>It creates a boundary-spanning role.</b>
      <c>It makes the company less fluid.</c>
      <d>It makes the company less responsive to customers.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What term is used for unique cognitive and emotional orientations among managers across functional departments, and the specialized formal structures among these departments?</q>
      <a>integration</a>
      <b>resource dependence</b>
      <c>cooptation</c>
      <d>differentiation</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What term is used to refer to high quality collaboration between departments?</q>
      <a>differentiation</a>
      <b>integration</b>
      <c>uncertainty</c>
      <d>cooptation</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following types of management processes do organizations in rapidly changing environments tend to have?</q>
      <a>differentiated</a>
      <b>mechanistic</b>
      <c>organic</c>
      <d>dependent</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following characterizes the mechanistic process?</q>
      <a>knowledge and control of tasks that are decentralized within the organization</a>
      <b>loosely defined tasks</b>
      <c>a strict hierarchy of authority and control</c>
      <d>horizontal communication</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which characteristic most accurately describes mechanistic organizations?</q>
      <a>They have authoritarian, unfriendly leadership.</a>
      <b>Communication is horizontal.</b>
      <c>They are service organizations with individualized customer demands.</c>
      <d>Tasks are broken down into specialized parts.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>High-moderate uncertainty environments are unstable but simple. Which of the following organizational responses are elicited by this environment?</q>
      <a>mechanistic structure; formal, centralized</a>
      <b>few buffering roles</b>
      <c>planning orientation; fast response</c>
      <d>many departments; few boundary spanning</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is an example of the way high uncertainty influences organizational design responses?</q>
      <a>requiring extensive planning and forecasting</a>
      <b>having few departments</b>
      <c>having no integrating roles</c>
      <d>using a mechanistic structure</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term refers to the idea that organizations need the environment but strive to minimize their vulnerabilities?</q>
      <a>integration</a>
      <b>resource dependence</b>
      <c>organic process</c>
      <d>cooptation</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is likely in organizations characterized by very simple and stable environments?</q>
      <a>almost no managers are assigned to integration roles</a>
      <b>many departments are added</b>
      <c>there is formal, centralized authority</c>
      <d>there is extensive planning, forecasting and high-speed responses</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term refers to the purchase of one organization by another so that the buyer assumes control?</q>
      <a>acquisition</a>
      <b>merger</b>
      <c>joint venture</c>
      <d>domain</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Dave Dunn is a militant member of a faculty union. When the unions negotiating committee is reporting to a meeting of the faculty, he always finds fault with the work of that committee and strongly advocates striking. When a member of the negotiating committee resigns because of illness, the unions executive committee appoints Dave to take his place. What is this is an example of?</q>
      <a>formal strategic alliance</a>
      <b>cooptation</b>
      <c>change of domain</c>
      <d>public relations</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>If an organization were engaging in illegitimate behaviours, which of the following might it be trying to do?</q>
      <a>control its environmental domain</a>
      <b>attempt to influence political activities</b>
      <c>change its domain</c>
      <d>cooptation of interlocking directorates</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is the term for a formal linkage that occurs when a member of the board of directors of one company sits on the board of directors of another company?</q>
      <a>joint venture</a>
      <b>interlocking directorate</b>
      <c>integration</c>
      <d>indirect interlock</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following occurs when leaders from important sectors in an organizations environment are asked to join that organization?</q>
      <a>integration</a>
      <b>joint venture</b>
      <c>resource dependence</c>
      <d>cooptation</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is especially important in highly competitive consumer industries and in industries that experience variable demand?</q>
      <a>advertising</a>
      <b>cooptation</b>
      <c>executive recruitment</c>
      <d>contracts</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>How can an organization change its domain most directly?</q>
      <a>by hiring a new CEO</a>
      <b>by changing the nature of the labourmanagement agreements</b>
      <c>by divesting a division of the organization</c>
      <d>by moving to a more favourable structure</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following can be used to erect regulatory barriers against new competitors or squash unfavourable legislation?</q>
      <a>cooptation</a>
      <b>contracts</b>
      <c>joint venture</c>
      <d>political strategy</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
  </chapter>
  <chapter num="5">
    <question>
      <q>Which term refers to relatively enduring resource transactions, flows, and linkages that occur among two or more organizations?</q>
      <a>intranet</a>
      <b>interorganizational relationships</b>
      <c>resource dependence</c>
      <d>institutional environment</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term refers to an entity formed by the interactions of a community of organizations and their environment?</q>
      <a>interorganizational relationship</a>
      <b>organizational ecosystem</b>
      <c>collaboration network</c>
      <d>institutional environment</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following do managers need to manage in an environment of a community of organizations?</q>
      <a>profit making</a>
      <b>stakeholders</b>
      <c>horizontal structures</c>
      <d>competition</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which perspective in the framework of interorganizational relationships represents the rational view?</q>
      <a>population ecology</a>
      <b>institutionalism</b>
      <c>collaborative network</c>
      <d>resource dependence</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which theory argues that organizations try to minimize their reliance on other organizations for the supply of important materials and try to influence the environment to make sure the materials they need are available?</q>
      <a>interorganizational theory</a>
      <b>environmental resource theory</b>
      <c>resource-dependence theory</c>
      <d>economic-supply theory</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following best defines resource dependence theory?</q>
      <a>A small supplier should count on price competition for locking in accounts.</a>
      <b>A small supplier should lock in a single large company for the bulk of its sales.</b>
      <c>Organizations will do whatever is needed to avoid dependence on the environment and increase their autonomy.</c>
      <d>Organizations will set up dependencies when they become more self-reliant.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is an organization engaging in if it joins a trade association because it is having difficulty securing the main raw material for its production process?</q>
      <a>interlocking directorships</a>
      <b>a power strategy</b>
      <c>a resource strategy</c>
      <d>collaborative networks</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Why might organizations enter into interorganizational collaborations?</q>
      <a>to share risks when entering new markets</a>
      <b>to assert power over larger suppliers</b>
      <c>to lock-in necessary resources</c>
      <d>to minimize interpersonal conflicts</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following did the traditional orientation to other organizations involve?</q>
      <a>long-term contracts</a>
      <b>participation in partners product design and production</b>
      <c>legal resolution of conflict</c>
      <d>electronic linkages to share key information</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a characteristic of the current orientation toward partnerships between other organizations?</q>
      <a>equity and fair dealing</a>
      <b>contracts limiting the relationship</b>
      <c>minimal up-front investment</c>
      <d>efficiency and the organizations own profits</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which approach focus(es) on organizational diversity and adaptation within a population of organizations?</q>
      <a>collaborative networks</a>
      <b>population ecology</b>
      <c>interorganizational relationships</c>
      <d>institutional perspective</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Why do established organizations have a difficult time adapting to a rapidly changing environment?</q>
      <a>They are inherently resistant to change.</a>
      <b>There is often a heavy investment in plant and equipment and leadership has an established viewpoint that has been successful.</b>
      <c>When the environment changes, no one can predict if the changes will affect them.</c>
      <d>Leadership could change its approach, but it does not want to change.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a basic assumption of the population ecology model?</q>
      <a>Management competence is the biggest factor in the survival of organizations.</a>
      <b>The environment determines which organizations survive or fail.</b>
      <c>Principles of evolution are not applicable to organizations because the fittest dont survive.</c>
      <d>A community of organizations is a closed system.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following provides the best description of an organizational niche?</q>
      <a>Once found, it makes the process of retention occur.</a>
      <b>It is a person within an organization who is highly specialized.</b>
      <c>It is a domain of unique environmental resources and needs.</c>
      <d>It is found only in Japanese organizations.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>As new organizational forms continue to emerge some fail and some last. Which of the following is the best label for this process?</q>
      <a>retention</a>
      <b>variation</b>
      <c>legitimacy</c>
      <d>selection</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which statement best describes the affect on organizational survival, as a principle underlying the population ecology model?</q>
      <a>Specialists are able to reallocate resources internally to adapt to a changing environment, whereas generalists are not.</a>
      <b>Generalists are more competitive than specialists in the narrow area in which their domains overlap.</b>
      <c>The toy company Mattel, which markets a broad range of toys, is considered a specialist.</c>
      <d>New organizations have lower survival rates due to environmental factors that tend to select them out of existence more often than existing organizations.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term is used to describe organizations with a wide domaini.e., those that offer a broad range of products and services or that serve a broad market?</q>
      <a>specialists</a>
      <b>generalists</b>
      <c>niches</c>
      <d>legitimate</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term is defined as the general perspective that an organizations actions are desirable, proper, and appropriate within the environments system of norms, values, and beliefs?</q>
      <a>generalist strategy</a>
      <b>legitimacy</b>
      <c>niche</c>
      <d>collaborative network</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is composed of norms and values from stakeholders?</q>
      <a>the institutional environment</a>
      <b>population ecology theory</b>
      <c>the organizational ecosystem</c>
      <d>institutional isomorphism</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What does the institutional view argue?</q>
      <a>Organizations do not have legitimacy from their stakeholders.</a>
      <b>A market-based economy was not constructed in Russia because its institutions were corrupt.</b>
      <c>When an organizational field is new, diversity is the norm, but later there is a pressure for them to be more similar.</c>
      <d>Organizations have two essential dimensions: institutional and public.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which statement best describes the institutional view of the two essential dimensions of organization?</q>
      <a>The institutional structure is that part of the organization most visible to the outside public.</a>
      <b>The public dimension of the institutional structure is governed by norms of efficiency.</b>
      <c>The technical dimension of the institutional structure will reflect environmental expectations rather than the demands of work activities.</c>
      <d>The formal institutional structure and design process is rational with respect to workflow and products.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following perspectives is included in institutional similarity?</q>
      <a>Common structures emerge among organizations in the same field.</a>
      <b>Common training of professionals (managers) results in common analytic processes among organizations in the same field.</b>
      <c>Divergent structures are driven among organizations in the same field for the sake of diversity.</c>
      <d>Divergent analytic processes among organizations in the same field emerge due to managers training in widely varying functional areas and varying degree programs.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following perspectives is included in mimetic forces?</q>
      <a>Because of heavy interorganizational linkages, organizations are forced to behave similarly in order to maintain productive relationships.</a>
      <b>Political and governmental processes, which organizations are subject to, force organizations to become similar.</b>
      <c>In the face of uncertainty, organizations copy or model each other.</c>
      <d>Diversity is maintained in order for organizations to find and maintain a marketing niche.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is one example of mimetic force?</q>
      <a>re-engineering</a>
      <b>accounting standards</b>
      <c>pollution controls</c>
      <d>consultant training</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which institutional process is being followed if an organization is engaged in benchmarking?</q>
      <a>mimetic process</a>
      <b>coercive process</b>
      <c>normative process</c>
      <d>isomorphic process</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is the reason for organizational structural adaptation due to coercive forces?</q>
      <a>dependence</a>
      <b>duty</b>
      <c>uncertainty</c>
      <d>professionalism</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is the social basis for normative forces?</q>
      <a>legal</a>
      <b>culture</b>
      <c>moral</c>
      <d>diversity</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is an example of a coercive force?</q>
      <a>professionalism</a>
      <b>innovation</b>
      <c>environmental visibility</c>
      <d>political law</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following do coercive forces result in?</q>
      <a>efficiency</a>
      <b>professionalism</b>
      <c>effectiveness</c>
      <d>the appearance of legitimacy</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following are organizations trying to gain when they become influenced by mimetic, coercive, or normative forces in the institutional environment??</q>
      <a>greater profit</a>
      <b>greater market share</b>
      <c>greater resource dependency</c>
      <d>greater legitimacy</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
  </chapter>
  <chapter num="6">
    <question>
      <q>What does building a global presence enable an organizations operations to achieve?</q>
      <a>economies of scale</a>
      <b>economies of scope</b>
      <c>factors of production</c>
      <d>its international development stage</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term refers to the number and variety of products and services a company offers, as well as the number and variety of regions, countries, and markets it serves?</q>
      <a>economies of scale</a>
      <b>market potential</b>
      <c>scope</c>
      <d>development stage</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which factor motivates companies to expand internationally and is related to labour and raw materials?</q>
      <a>cheaper production</a>
      <b>smaller number of distribution channels</b>
      <c>economies of scale</c>
      <d>economies of scope</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>In what stage does a specific division replace the export department, requiring the need to hire specialists to handle sales, service, and warehousing abroad?</q>
      <a>domestic</a>
      <b>international</b>
      <c>global</c>
      <d>multinational</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>In what stage of the international evolution of a company are the worldwide geographic or product structures most likely to appear?</q>
      <a>domestic</a>
      <b>international</b>
      <c>multinational</c>
      <d>global</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which types of organizations operate with the entire world as their marketplace?</q>
      <a>multidomestic firms</a>
      <b>domestic organizations</b>
      <c>governmental agencies</c>
      <d>global companies</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a popular approach to sharing development and production costs and penetrating new markets?</q>
      <a>consortia</a>
      <b>licensing</b>
      <c>joint ventures</c>
      <d>franchising</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is the term for groups of independent companies that come together to share skills, resources, costs, and access to one anothers markets?</q>
      <a>joint ventures</a>
      <b>cartels</b>
      <c>alliances</c>
      <d>consortia</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a new entity that is created when two or more separate firms come together to share development and/or production costs?</q>
      <a>wholly owned subsidiaries</a>
      <b>joint ventures</b>
      <c>consortia</c>
      <d>licensing agreements</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What type of strategy is being followed when a company such as Coca-Cola decides to use the same product design and advertising strategy throughout the world?</q>
      <a>multidomestic</a>
      <b>consortia</b>
      <c>focused</c>
      <d>globalization</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which type of strategy would encourage production design, assembly, and marketing tailored to the needs of each country?</q>
      <a>focused</a>
      <b>multidomestic</b>
      <c>globalization</c>
      <d>joint venture</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>With what kind of products does the global product structure work best?</q>
      <a>products that are technologically dissimilar</a>
      <b>products that can be standardized for marketing worldwide</b>
      <c>products that are obsolete in one country, but not in another</c>
      <d>products that are cheap and easy to produce</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a characteristic of the global product organizational structure?</q>
      <a>It utilizes country managers who are accountable for profit and loss of every product.</a>
      <b>It fits well with customization of production or marketing.</b>
      <c>It may result in competition among product divisions.</c>
      <d>It will ensure that all countries are covered well.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a characteristic of the global geographical organizational structure?</q>
      <a>It is most useful for new product lines.</a>
      <b>It works well for products with rapidly changing technologies.</b>
      <c>It works best if there are similar needs for the product across countries.</c>
      <d>It may make product planning on a global scale challenging.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a characteristic of the global matrix organizational structure?</q>
      <a>It increases horizontal coordination, but decreases vertical coordination.</a>
      <b>It balances the interests of both product standardization and regional customization</b>
      <c>It commonly utilizes matrix bosses as functional and product heads.</c>
      <d>It divides the world into regions with each division reporting to the CEO.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Refer to Chart 6.1. Which of the following best describes the organization depicted in Chart 6.1?</q>
      <a>Law, engineering, and finance are considered to be product groups.</a>
      <b>The regional directors are also responsible for product groups.</b>
      <c>Global product heads fulfill the function of full-time staff integrators.</c>
      <d>Global product heads are usually accountable for profit and loss of their product in worldwide sales.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Refer to Chart 6.1. Which structure is shown?</q>
      <a>global geographic</a>
      <b>global matrix</b>
      <c>global product</c>
      <d>global functional</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Refer to Chart 6.2. How would you relate the structure diagrammed in organizational chart 6.2 to a global geographic structure?</q>
      <a>The firm shown above is not as far along in developing opportunities for multidomestic strategy as the global geographic structure would be.</a>
      <b>Product managers differ in that, in the chart above, the product heads are line managers primarily accountable for their product domestically, whereas, in the global geographic structure, product heads are staff advisers.</b>
      <c>The structure shown is better than the global geographic structure.</c>
      <d>The global geographic structure is more domestically oriented than the one above.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Refer to Chart 6.2. Which structure is shown?</q>
      <a>global functional</a>
      <b>domestic hybrid</b>
      <c>global matrix</c>
      <d>global product</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which component of the global organizational challenge is being faced by an organization that has to create a structure to operate in numerous countries that differ in economic development, language, political systems and government regulations, cultural norms and values, and infrastructure?</q>
      <a>the problem of transferring knowledge across a global firm</a>
      <b>dealing with greater complexity and differentiation</b>
      <c>the need for integration</c>
      <d>the need for KSAs</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What kind of major challenge do managers face as organizations become more differentiated, with multiple products, divisions, departments, and positions scattered across numerous countries?</q>
      <a>knowledge transfer</a>
      <b>differentiation</b>
      <c>integration</c>
      <d>development</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Lawrence Incorporated used global teams as part of its internationalization, enabling them to be more locally responsive to different regional markets, consumer preferences, and political and legal systems. Which of the following issues did this structure address?</q>
      <a>the differentiation challenge</a>
      <b>units gaining influence within the global firm</b>
      <c>codification of organizational knowledge throughout the global firm</c>
      <d>lack of ability to gain economies of scope</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following kinds of formal positions do organizations create to coordinate information and activities related to key customer accounts?</q>
      <a>functional manager</a>
      <b>transnational team</b>
      <c>network coordinator</c>
      <d>division network</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following, if present to a high degree, means that people accept inequality among institutions, organizations, and people?</q>
      <a>uncertainty avoidance</a>
      <b>power distance</b>
      <c>employee empowerment</c>
      <d>integration</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which statement best describes Mandel-Campbells description of Canadas approach to competing globally?</q>
      <a>Canada has competed effectively internationally.</a>
      <b>Canada needs policies to encourage entrepreneurial action.</b>
      <c>Canada needs to do more research to understand and address globalization.</c>
      <d>Canadian companies have not had the gumption necessary for international success.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which model reflects the ultimate in both organizational complexity, with many diverse units, and organizational coordination, with mechanisms for integrating the varied parts?</q>
      <a>transformative</a>
      <b>transnational</b>
      <c>global</c>
      <d>multidomestic</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following characterizes the transnational model?</q>
      <a>using shared vision and values to achieve coordination in this horizontal structure</a>
      <b>being one step short of the matrix in exploiting both global and local advantages for the corporation as well as multiple interrelated competitive issues</b>
      <c>having a single headquarter and a single centre of control for each country and for each product line</c>
      <d>not having a single corporate headquarter, but a clear hierarchical responsibility</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following characteristics distinguishes the transnational organization from other forms of global organizations?</q>
      <a>Assets and resources are dispersed worldwide into highly specialized operations that are linked through interdependent relationships.</a>
      <b>Structures are stable.</b>
      <c>Subsidiary managers initiate strategy and innovations that become strategy for the corporation as a whole.</c>
      <d>Unification and coordination are achieved primarily through corporate culture, shared vision and values, and management style rather than through formal structures and systems.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
  </chapter>
  <chapter num="7">
    <question>
      <q>Woodwards classification of technology (into three clusters of organizational technologies) was based on a scale. What did that scale measure?</q>
      <a>the number of employees in the span of control</a>
      <b>the interdependence of tasks</b>
      <c>the technological complexity of the organizations technical core</c>
      <d>the variety and analyzability of tasks within each department</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which kind of production represents mechanization and standardization one step beyond those in an assembly line?</q>
      <a>continuous process</a>
      <b>large-batch</b>
      <c>technical complexity</c>
      <d>small-batch</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which type of system links manufacturing components that previously stood alone?</q>
      <a>continuous process systems</a>
      <b>flexible manufacturing systems</b>
      <c>advance technological systems</c>
      <d>computerized process systems</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What are the three subcomponents of computer-integrated manufacturing?</q>
      <a>CAD, CAM, and integration information network</a>
      <b>people, hardware, and software</b>
      <c>information, computers, and procedures</c>
      <d>CIM, ADC, and software</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is one important advantage of flexible manufacturing systems</q>
      <a>It requires little training to use.</a>
      <b>There is little employee involvement.</b>
      <c>One product can be produced at a time, making it easier for employees to operate.</c>
      <d>Products of different sizes, types, and customer requirements freely intermingle on the assembly line.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is based on employee involvement?</q>
      <a>mass customization</a>
      <b>FMS</b>
      <c>lean manufacturing</c>
      <d>CAD</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What sort of organization is a retail store such as HBC an example of?</q>
      <a>customer service</a>
      <b>product and service</b>
      <c>product focused</c>
      <d>product consuming</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which type of process is used in the production of an intangible product?</q>
      <a>service technology</a>
      <b>flexible manufacturing systems</b>
      <c>lean manufacturing</c>
      <d>non-core departmental technology</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>How can service organizations achieve their greatest economies?</q>
      <a>through centralization of services</a>
      <b>through geographic decentralization</b>
      <c>through dividing into smaller units close to customers</c>
      <d>through centralized decision making</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term means providing exactly the service each customer wants and needs?</q>
      <a>service complexity</a>
      <b>customized output</b>
      <c>mass customization</c>
      <d>CAM</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term is used to refer to the frequency of unexpected and novel events that occur in the conversion process?</q>
      <a>service technologies</a>
      <b>non-routine technologies</b>
      <c>task variety</c>
      <d>analyzability</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is Perrow most concerned with?</q>
      <a>two aspects of technology: variety and analyzability</a>
      <b>two types of structures that seem to determine which technology is best</b>
      <c>two aspects of environment that call for a particular structure</c>
      <d>two types of structures that seem to determine which environment should be enacted</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What kind of technology is employed by an oil explorer using a divining rod to decide where to begin drilling operations?</q>
      <a>routine</a>
      <b>craft</b>
      <c>engineering</c>
      <d>high analyzability</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Using Perrows framework, in which category would you most likely find the public relations departmenti.e., the outreach arm for all media and community relations?</q>
      <a>craft</a>
      <b>nonroutine</b>
      <c>engineering</c>
      <d>routine</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>The verification department of the federal tax department checks the mathematics on returns and notes any discrepancies. Which of Perrows quadrants would this department fit into?</q>
      <a>craft</a>
      <b>routine</b>
      <c>engineering</c>
      <d>nonroutine</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>According to the general pattern in technology research, what is advisable when technologies are routine, analyzable, independent, and well defined?</q>
      <a>Organic structures with less control, fewer procedures, decentralized decision making, and face-to-face communications should be used.</a>
      <b>A sociotechnical approach should be used.</b>
      <c>Mechanistic structures with tighter control, formalized procedures, centralized decision making, and written communications are appropriate.</c>
      <d>Coordination must be achieved through CIM.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Judy has 300 employees reporting to her, whereas 25 employees report to Fred. Which of the following statements provides the best comparison of the two?</q>
      <a>Judy has a more narrow span of control than Fred.</a>
      <b>Judys organization has less formalization than Freds.</b>
      <c>Judys employees are less skilled than Freds.</c>
      <d>Judy has a wider span of control than Fred.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Jane works for a college that offers correspondence courses. She works in the mailroom stuffing envelopes with the replies of professors to students. She then seals the envelopes and puts them in an outgoing bin. She finds that on this job she has a lot of time for daydreaming. What would you expect the organizational structure in her department to be?</q>
      <a>mechanistic</a>
      <b>organic</b>
      <c>high in variety</c>
      <d>unanalyzable</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Suppose that VW is considering changing its production operations from an assembly line in which each employee adds one piece as a car chassis goes by to an operation in which several employees work as a team to build the complete car, with the team deciding who does what tasks. If VW implements the change, how would interrelationships change?</q>
      <a>from pooled interdependence on the line to reciprocal interdependence between the teams</a>
      <b>from reciprocal interdependence on the line to sequential interdependence between the teams</b>
      <c>from sequential interdependence on the line to pooled interdependence between the teams</c>
      <d>from routine tasks to mediating technology</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>When work does not flow between units and each unit works independently, the units are said to have which of the following types of interdependence?</q>
      <a>pooled interdependence</a>
      <b>grouped interdependence</b>
      <c>sequential interdependence</c>
      <d>high interdependence</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>A building contractor is constructing 35 tract homes on small, adjoining parcels. The crew knows that the many subcontractors must complete their work in a proper order. What is your recommendation regarding the level of coordination required?</q>
      <a>Because this is pooled interdependence, rules from the construction industry should suffice, since everyone on the job can learn the rules for the proper ordering of subcontractors.</a>
      <b>Because this is reciprocal interdependence, cross-functional teams among all the subcontractors will be essential.</b>
      <c>Because this is sequential interdependence, regularly scheduled meetings and planning will be needed to coordinate the ordering of the work.</c>
      <d>Because this is a sociotechnical system, it is most important to design the coordination to improve efficiency, ignoring human needs.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>For which of the following would baseball be a close analogy?</q>
      <a>sequential interdependence</a>
      <b>pooled interdependence</b>
      <c>reciprocal interdependence</c>
      <d>the highest level of team interdependence</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What form of interdependence would apply to a game of football?</q>
      <a>pooled because management must select individual players and develop their skills</a>
      <b>sequential because plays are run sequentially and events during the plays occur sequentially</b>
      <c>reciprocal because mutual adjustments must be made by the players</c>
      <d>sporadic, because it is really a game of individual talents</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following includes the assignment of goals and tasks to be accomplished by employees?</q>
      <a>job rotation</a>
      <b>job coordination</b>
      <c>job exchange</c>
      <d>job design</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following means that the job provides greater responsibility, recognition, and opportunities for growth and development?</q>
      <a>job enrichment</a>
      <b>job rotation</b>
      <c>job design</c>
      <d>job simplification</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What impact have advanced technologies had on job design?</q>
      <a>job simplification</a>
      <b>no change</b>
      <c>job enrichment</c>
      <d>lowered wages</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following has resulted from the impact of technology on job design?</q>
      <a>job simplification</a>
      <b>greater division of labour</b>
      <c>jobs requiring higher-level skills</c>
      <d>lower compensation because of the financial emphasis on equipment</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term means that an organization functions best only when the social and technical systems are defined to fit the needs of one another?</q>
      <a>job design</a>
      <b>joint optimization</b>
      <c>coordination</c>
      <d>task variety</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is the purpose of the sociotechnical systems approach?</q>
      <a>to apply the theory of job enlargement</a>
      <b>to provide qualified management to an organization in a turbulent environment</b>
      <c>to offer the most advanced information technology possible to maximize organizational competitiveness</c>
      <d>to combine human needs with technical efficiency in job design</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is the goal of the sociotechnical systems approach?</q>
      <a>to design the organization for joint optimization</a>
      <b>to design the organization for re-engineering</b>
      <c>to design the organization for self-regulation of advanced technology</c>
      <d>to design the organization for strong organization culture</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is the core principle underlying the sociotechnical systems approach that refers to the iterative process of design?</q>
      <a>incompletion</a>
      <b>reciprocal interdependence</b>
      <c>support congruence</c>
      <d>variance control</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
  </chapter>
  <chapter num="8">
    <question>
      <q>In what area did organizations initially apply information technology?</q>
      <a>decision support systems</a>
      <b>transaction processing systems</b>
      <c>management information systems</c>
      <d>enterprise resource planning systems</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What types of systems are used to automate an organizations routine, day-to-day business activities such as data from sales or purchases from suppliers?</q>
      <a>transaction processing systems</a>
      <b>automated analysis systems</b>
      <c>inventory control systems</c>
      <d>decision support systems</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Who is typically concerned with well-defined problems about operational issues and past events?</q>
      <a>top management</a>
      <b>first-line management</b>
      <c>employees</c>
      <d>middle management</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following terms refers to the use of huge databases that combine all of a companys data and allow users to access the data directly, create reports, and obtain responses to what-if questions?</q>
      <a>data analytics</a>
      <b>data processing</b>
      <c>data storing</c>
      <d>data warehousing</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What software uses sophisticated decision-making processes to search raw data for patterns and relationships that may be significant?</q>
      <a>search algorithms</a>
      <b>data mining</b>
      <c>analytical</c>
      <d>decision support systems</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is the highest level of application of information technology?</q>
      <a>for internal control for profitability</a>
      <b>external application for new business forms</b>
      <c>adding strategic value</c>
      <d>for networking</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is an interactive information system designed to help managers at all levels make decisions through integrated databases in which a series of what-if questions can be posed?</q>
      <a>decision support systems</a>
      <b>transaction processing systems</b>
      <c>management information systems</c>
      <d>information linkages</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following provides mid-level managers with reports that summarize data and support day-to-day decision making?</q>
      <a>executive information systems</a>
      <b>decision support systems</b>
      <c>information reporting systems</c>
      <d>feedback control systems</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following are typically based on software that can convert large amounts of complex data into pertinent information and provide that information to top managers in a timely fashion?</q>
      <a>decision support systems</a>
      <b>executive information systems</b>
      <c>information reporting systems</c>
      <d>TPS</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following steps in a simplified feedback control model refers to setting targets?</q>
      <a>take corrective action as needed</a>
      <b>establish standards of performance</b>
      <c>measure actual performance and compare to standards</c>
      <d>set organizational mission and vision</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is (are) defined as the formal routines, reports, and procedures that use information to maintain or alter patterns in organizational activities?</q>
      <a>management control systems</a>
      <b>management information systems</b>
      <c>decision support systems</c>
      <d>feedback control systems</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following best describes the formal routines, reports, and procedures that use information to maintain or alter patterns in organization activities?</q>
      <a>feedback control model</a>
      <b>management control system</b>
      <c>discipline policies</c>
      <d>executive information system</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What term is used for the process of continually measuring products, services, and practices against those of tough competitors or other organizations recognized as industry leaders?</q>
      <a>the balanced scorecard</a>
      <b>benchmarking</b>
      <c>Six Sigma</c>
      <d>enterprise resource planning</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a highly ambitious quality standard that specifies a goal of no more than 3.4 defects per million parts?</q>
      <a>benchmarking</a>
      <b>the balanced scorecard</b>
      <c>knowledge management</c>
      <d>Six Sigma</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Six Sigma is based on a methodology that provides a structured way for organizations to approach and solve problems. What is the methodology?</q>
      <a>define, measure, analyze, improve, control</a>
      <b>data warehousing</b>
      <c>executive information systems</c>
      <d>benchmarking</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following specify standards for employee participation, teamwork, and problem solving?</q>
      <a>employee reward programs</a>
      <b>quality control systems</b>
      <c>reward systems</c>
      <d>statistical reports</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is (are) a comprehensive management control system that balances traditional financial measures with operational measures relating to a companys critical success factors?</q>
      <a>benchmarking</a>
      <b>balanced scorecards</b>
      <c>management control systems</c>
      <d>Six Sigma</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a key performance indicator of a balanced scorecard?</q>
      <a>benchmarking</a>
      <b>business process indicators</b>
      <c>corporate social responsibility measures</c>
      <d>the organizations capacity for learning and growth</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following helps managers focus on the key strategic measures that define the success of a particular organization over time and communicate them clearly through the organization?</q>
      <a>networking</a>
      <b>data warehousing</b>
      <c>enterprise resource planning</c>
      <d>the balanced scorecard</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>How is access to management information systems and executive information systems typically controlled?</q>
      <a>by placing them on the Internet</a>
      <b>by placing them on individual PCs of authorized managers</b>
      <c>by placing them on an intranet</c>
      <d>by placing them on an extranet</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What term is used for the form of corporate networking that is a private internal network using the infrastructure of the World Wide Web but cordoned off from the public?</q>
      <a>webnet</a>
      <b>intranet</b>
      <c>interweb</c>
      <d>CorpNet</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is the term for the efforts to systematically find, organize, and make available a companys intellectual capital and to foster a culture of continuous learning and knowledge sharing so that organizational activities build on what is already known?</q>
      <a>enterprise resource planning</a>
      <b>Six Sigma</b>
      <c>knowledge management</c>
      <d>benchmarking</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is intellectual capital?</q>
      <a>intellectual property</a>
      <b>the sum of an organizations knowledge, experience, etc.</b>
      <c>innovations made by in-house professionals</c>
      <d>intangible assets</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is an example of explicit knowledge?</q>
      <a>investing time at meetings in the sharing of stories and learning of histories</a>
      <b>a strong feel for the corporate culture</b>
      <c>an electronic document system that codifies, stores, disseminates, and allows reuse of knowledge</c>
      <d>channelling individual expertise to provide creative advice on problem solving</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is an important aspect of an integrated enterprise?</q>
      <a>Six Sigma</a>
      <b>networking</b>
      <c>supply-chain management</c>
      <d>the intranet</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following can create a level of cooperation if managers approach it with an attitude of trust and partnership?</q>
      <a>enterprise integration</a>
      <b>networking</b>
      <c>knowledge management</c>
      <d>enterprise resource planning</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following basic strategies for setting up an Internet operation represents the middle road of the organizational design spectrum?</q>
      <a>in-house divisions</a>
      <b>strategic partnerships</b>
      <c>spinoff companies</c>
      <d>franchising</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is one impact information technology has had on organizational design?</q>
      <a>larger size</a>
      <b>more decentralized organizational structures</b>
      <c>technology as a substitute for professional staff, thereby decreasing the need for them</c>
      <d>decreased levels of employee participation</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What happens to most activities in a modular structure?</q>
      <a>They are outsourced.</a>
      <b>They are eliminated.</b>
      <c>They are performed by in-house professionals.</c>
      <d>They are simplified.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
  </chapter>
  <chapter num="9">
    <question>
      <q>What are small businesses characterized by, in contrast to large businesses?</q>
      <a>niche-finding strategies</a>
      <b>a decreasing percentage of employees in the economy as a whole</b>
      <c>fewer numbers, as merger mania continues to create a larger proportion of large firms in the world economy</c>
      <d>the front/back combinations that combine small units into larger ones</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is the major goal of an organization during the entrepreneurial stage of the life cycle?</q>
      <a>growth</a>
      <b>goal-setting</b>
      <c>survival</c>
      <d>complete organizational structure</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following best describes organizations going through the organizational life cycle?</q>
      <a>They usually reach elaboration in 1218 months.</a>
      <b>They tend to become very bureaucratic by the collectivity stage.</b>
      <c>They usually resolve crises associated with each stage, or face restricted growth.</c>
      <d>They tend to experience their wildest and most rapid growth period in the formalization stage.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>When do organizations begin to develop clear goals and direction?</q>
      <a>entrepreneurial stage</a>
      <b>elaboration stage</b>
      <c>formalization stage</c>
      <d>collectivity stage</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>At which stage in the life cycle of a newly established hierarchy do departments emerge and get established, along with the beginnings of division of labour?</q>
      <a>entrepreneurial</a>
      <b>formalization</b>
      <c>collectivity</c>
      <d>elaboration</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a characteristic of the formalization stage of the organizational life cycle?</q>
      <a>frequent communication</a>
      <b>top management concern with planning and strategy</b>
      <c>establishment of departments</c>
      <d>market survival</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Two brothers, Jake and Tommy, were hired by an organization with a bureaucratic organizational structure. Because they had different sets of skills, they ended up working in different parts of the organization. Which dimension of bureaucracy is this an example of?</q>
      <a>rules and procedures</a>
      <b>specialization and division of labour</b>
      <c>hierarchy of authority</c>
      <d>trained employees</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Why did Max Weber develop the concept of a bureaucracy?</q>
      <a>to make organizations more rational and efficient</a>
      <b>to make organizations more empathetic</b>
      <c>to make organizations less formal</c>
      <d>to make organizations quicker to respond to stakeholders</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What was the purpose of rules and standard procedures as developed by Weber?</q>
      <a>to help managers get tough with lazy employees</a>
      <b>to keep managers in their positions of control and power</b>
      <c>to enable activities to be performed in a predictable and routine manner</c>
      <d>to punish anyone who got out of line</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which crisis is associated with the collectivity stage of the organizational life cycle?</q>
      <a>need for leadership</a>
      <b>need for delegation with control</b>
      <c>need to deal with too much red tape</c>
      <d>need for revitalization</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What has research on personnel ratios found?</q>
      <a>that clerical and professional support staff ratios decrease in proportion to organization size</a>
      <b>that small organizations are very inefficient because direct workers as a percentage of total employees are so low</b>
      <c>that personnel ratios for professional support staff are higher in small firms than in large firms</c>
      <d>that there is a smaller administrative ratio in large firms</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Tyler Jones is the CEO of a medium-sized manufacturer of bedding and blankets. Tyler insists on making all decisions on what styles are manufactured; the type of material that will be used in each; the sources from which the company will purchase yard goods, thread, and buttons; and the shippers the company will use. Which of the following terms describes this company?</q>
      <a>routinized</a>
      <b>centralized</b>
      <c>formalized</c>
      <d>standardized</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is high formalization most closely associated with?</q>
      <a>organic structure</a>
      <b>bureaucracy</b>
      <c>large size</c>
      <d>responsive style</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is the primary reason the CEO of a large company such as Tim Hortons would push decisions as far down the hierarchy as he or she can?</q>
      <a>to develop managers</a>
      <b>to make decisions more quickly</b>
      <c>to appear more Canadian and thereby increase sales</c>
      <d>to save himself or herself the trouble of making these decisions</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Carson is the manager of Cutters Consulting, a consulting company comprised of professionals from different fields. What would Carson be wise to do in such a company?</q>
      <a>bring the organization immediately into revitalization</a>
      <b>have little formalization</b>
      <c>use as much authority as much as possible</c>
      <d>discourage horizontal communication because it violates the chain of command</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following was developed to maintain the efficiency and control benefits of bureaucracy yet prevent the problem of slow response to crises?</q>
      <a>big-small hybrid</a>
      <b>market control</b>
      <c>clan control</c>
      <d>incident command system</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is based on the idea that the organization can glide smoothly between a highly formalized, hierarchical structure that is effective during times of stability and a more flexible, loosely structured hierarchy when needed to respond well to unexpected and demanding environmental conditions?</q>
      <a>decentralization</a>
      <b>incident command system</b>
      <c>clan control</c>
      <d>formalization</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>In the incident command system, who or what ensures all activities that occur are appropriate?</q>
      <a>clan control</a>
      <b>the professional partnership</b>
      <c>the incident commander</c>
      <d>bureaucratic control</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What term is used for a relatively new form of organization that includes medical practices and law firms?</q>
      <a>incident commanders</a>
      <b>clan members</b>
      <c>professional collaborations</c>
      <d>professional partnerships</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term is defined as the use of rules, policies, hierarchy of authority, written documentation, standardization, and other mechanisms to standardize behaviour and assess performance?</q>
      <a>market control</a>
      <b>bureaucratic control</b>
      <c>traditional control</c>
      <d>clan control</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which type of authority refers to employees belief in the legality of rules and the right of those elevated to positions of authority to issue commands?</q>
      <a>charismatic authority</a>
      <b>rational-legal authority</b>
      <c>traditional authority</c>
      <d>competitive authority</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Larry is a great leader who has run his organization for many years, and has the kind of personality that everyone wants to be around. What type of authority does Larry have?</q>
      <a>rational-legal</a>
      <b>traditional</b>
      <c>charismatic</c>
      <d>informal</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which type of authority is the most widely used form to govern internal work activities and decision making, particularly in large organizations?</q>
      <a>traditional</a>
      <b>charismatic</b>
      <c>appointed</c>
      <d>rational-legal</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Shellis organization operates in an industry with a great deal of competition that produces a commodity-type product. She measures success based on cost control and profit maximization. Which form of control does she use?</q>
      <a>bureaucratic</a>
      <b>clan</b>
      <c>traditional</c>
      <d>market</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>In what kind of organizations is clan control most often used?</q>
      <a>small, informal organizations or ones with a strong culture</a>
      <b>small, formal organizations or ones with a weak culture</b>
      <c>large, informal organizations or ones with a weak culture</c>
      <d>large, formal organizations or ones with a strong culture</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What term is used for a condition in which a substantial, absolute change in an organizations resource base occurs over a period of time?</q>
      <a>organization dissolution</a>
      <b>organizational life-cycle</b>
      <c>organizational decline</c>
      <d>organizational inaction</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a factor that causes organizational decline?</q>
      <a>vulnerability</a>
      <b>increased product prices</b>
      <c>increased market control</c>
      <d>organizational realignment</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>In which stage does denial occur despite signs of deteriorating performance?</q>
      <a>the blinded stage</a>
      <b>the inaction stage</b>
      <c>the faulty action stage</c>
      <d>the crisis stage</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>In what stage does the organization face serious problems, and indicators of poor performance can no longer be ignored?</q>
      <a>the faulty action stage</a>
      <b>the dissolution stage</b>
      <c>the blinded stage</c>
      <d>the crisis stage</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>When downsizing, which of the following helps eases the downsizing process and reduces tension of both employees who leave and those who remain?</q>
      <a>helping the remaining employees focus on their daily tasks by providing more guidance or assistance</a>
      <b>communicating less, not more</b>
      <c>providing assistance to workers who were let go</c>
      <d>letting workers deal with the situation on their own and in their own way</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
  </chapter>
  <chapter num="10">
    <question>
      <q>Why is it that organizations do NOT typically come face-to-face with the power of culture until they try to implement new strategies or programs that go against basic cultural norms and values?</q>
      <a>Culture is usually written and when a change is attempted written cultural policies create obstacles to change.</a>
      <b>Culture provides members with a sense of self and members rely on this sense and are therefore resistant to change.</b>
      <c>Culture generates commitment to improving market share and a change that alters culture leads to reduced revenues.</c>
      <d>Culture generally goes unnoticed until a change is made and the power becomes noticeable.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What are the two levels where culture exists?</q>
      <a>sub- and super-structure</a>
      <b>people and structure</b>
      <c>underlying values and visible artifacts</c>
      <d>social and psychological</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term means that members develop a collective identity and know how to work together effectively?</q>
      <a>external adaptation</a>
      <b>socialization</b>
      <c>internal integration</c>
      <d>cultural identity</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following are manifestations of organizational culture?</q>
      <a>legends</a>
      <b>control systems</b>
      <c>structures</c>
      <d>management information systems</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>When students finish their studies at a college, they go through a graduation ceremony with the idea of soon finding a new social role. Which kind of rite is this an example of?</q>
      <a>rite of passage</a>
      <b>rite of enhancement</b>
      <c>rite of renewal</c>
      <d>rite of integration</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is an example of the rite of integration in organizational culture?</q>
      <a>an award given to the employee of the month</a>
      <b>unpaid three-week orientation and training for prospective (new) employees</b>
      <c>an office BBQ</c>
      <d>organizational development activities</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What are stories that are used to perpetuate culture in organizations based on?</q>
      <a>anything that reeks of symbolism</a>
      <b>nothing in fact, but on the ideals of the organization</b>
      <c>true events</c>
      <d>unsubstantiated rumours</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is Van Hornes statement If we cant export the scenery, well import the tourists! an example of?</q>
      <a>a story</a>
      <b>a myth</b>
      <c>a symbol</c>
      <d>language</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following best describes the culture at 3M, a company whose values promote individual initiative and entrepreneurship?</q>
      <a>an adaptability culture</a>
      <b>a mission culture</b>
      <c>a clan culture</c>
      <d>a bureaucratic culture</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which kind of leader would thrive in a clan culture?</q>
      <a>one who creates values for social responsibility</a>
      <b>one who embodies values</b>
      <c>one who integrates people into action and responsibility through participation</c>
      <d>one who can change culture</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What does the mission culture put major emphasis on?</q>
      <a>the external environment through flexibility and change to meet customer needs</a>
      <b>a shared vision of organizational purpose</b>
      <c>the involvement and participation of the organizations members</c>
      <d>the internal environment and a consistency orientation for a stable environment</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which kind of culture has an internal focus and a consistency orientation for a stable environment?</q>
      <a>organic</a>
      <b>clan</b>
      <c>traditional</c>
      <d>bureaucratic</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Why are most organizations trying to move away from bureaucratic cultures?</q>
      <a>the need for greater flexibility</a>
      <b>the need for better decision-making techniques</b>
      <c>the need for easier communication channels</c>
      <d>the need for reducing employee participation</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term is used to refer to the degree of agreement among members of an organization about the importance of specific values?</q>
      <a>adaptability</a>
      <b>culture strength</b>
      <c>internal integration</c>
      <d>social responsibility</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following develop in response to common problems, goals, and experiences shared by members of a team, department, or other unit?</q>
      <a>learning organizations</a>
      <b>ethical committees</b>
      <c>subcultures</c>
      <d>ethics hotlines</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following values best characterize a learning organization?</q>
      <a>the whole being more important than the part, and boundaries between parts being minimized</a>
      <b>external strategic focus with continual thoughts of what others are doing thats right</b>
      <c>life-time employment for workers at every level (unless a work rule is violated)</c>
      <d>an internal efficiency focus</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is at play when behaviour is governed by a set of moral principles and values?</q>
      <a>the rule of law</a>
      <b>ethics</b>
      <c>a mission environment</c>
      <d>a vision statement</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following arise(s) from a set of codified principles and regulations that describe how people are required to act, that are generally accepted in society, and that are enforceable in the courts?</q>
      <a>code of ethics</a>
      <b>rule of law</b>
      <c>core values</c>
      <d>managerial ethics</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Every day, business people make choices about whether to be honest or deceitful with suppliers, treat employees with respect or disdain, and be a good or a harmful corporate citizen. Which of the following guides these decisions?</q>
      <a>managerial ethics</a>
      <b>whistle-blowing policies</b>
      <c>codes of ethics</c>
      <d>cultural norms</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following arises in a situation concerning right and wrong when values differ?</q>
      <a>culture problem</a>
      <b>legal issue</b>
      <c>social responsibility issue</c>
      <d>ethical dilemma</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is the major force that shapes managerial ethics?</q>
      <a>organizational culture</a>
      <b>external shareholders</b>
      <c>peers</c>
      <d>legal systems</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which framework argues that decisions should be made to promote fairness and equity?</q>
      <a>utilitarian theory</a>
      <b>personal liberty</b>
      <c>distributive justice</c>
      <d>eternal law</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Various representatives of which of the following influence managerial ethics and social responsibility?</q>
      <a>external stakeholders</a>
      <b>employees</b>
      <c>competitors</c>
      <d>whistle-blowers</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term refers to a situation in which the relationship between a manager and followers is based on shared, strongly internalized beliefs that are advocated and acted upon by the manager?</q>
      <a>mission culture</a>
      <b>values-based leadership</b>
      <c>clan culture</c>
      <d>servant leadership</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is an example of formal structure and formal systems that can be used to shape ethical values?</q>
      <a>patterning from senior management</a>
      <b>repetition of words such as those ending Wal-Marts cheer: Whos No. 1? The Customer!</b>
      <c>a whistle-blowing disclosure mechanism</c>
      <d>values-based leadership</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Why did Citigroup implement a statement of cultural and ethical values after being stung by a series of scandals?</q>
      <a>A formal statement of the companys values relates to the unobservable but important organizational culture.</a>
      <b>A formal statement of values can serve as a fundamental organizational document that defines what the organization stands for.</b>
      <c>A formal statement addresses ethical values rather than specific behaviours.</c>
      <d>A formal statement is often part of a larger mission statement and therefore is taken for granted.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is an attribute of a culture of discipline?</q>
      <a>level 5 leadership</a>
      <b>organizational values of collective autonomy</b>
      <c>focus on greater flexibility</c>
      <d>laissez-faire management</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
  </chapter>
  <chapter num="11">
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following occurs mainly through the established structure and management processes of an organization?</q>
      <a>evolution of the organizational culture</a>
      <b>incremental change</b>
      <c>technology improvements</c>
      <d>radical change</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is best example of radical change?</q>
      <a>organizational turnarounds and transformations</a>
      <b>any series of continual progressive changes affecting one organizational part, and then another</b>
      <c>implementation of sales teams in the marketing department</c>
      <d>bringing new technology to product development</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>If an organization shifts its structure from a vertical to a horizontal structure, what type of change have they engaged in?</q>
      <a>radical change</a>
      <b>incremental change</b>
      <c>Information technology change</c>
      <d>strategy and structure change</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Why does radical change likely involve breakthrough technology?</q>
      <a>It occurs through an unestablished structure.</a>
      <b>Technology change represents a series of continuous progressions for maintaining the organizations general equilibrium.</b>
      <c>d.</c>
      <d>Radical change often involves the creation of new products that lead the organization into new opportunities and markets.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>ABC Credit Union began offering a Sweep Account in which funds over $500 in a chequing account would be swept into a money-market, interest-bearing account until the chequing account reached $100, at which point funds from the money market account would be swept back into the chequing account. What type of change is this an example of?</q>
      <a>product or service</a>
      <b>radical</b>
      <c>incremental</c>
      <d>product improvement</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What term is used for the adoption of an idea or behaviour new to the companys industry, market, or general environment?</q>
      <a>the ambidextrous approach</a>
      <b>the dual-core approach</b>
      <c>strategy and structure change</c>
      <d>organizational innovation</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is one of the four strategic types of change highlighted in your text?</q>
      <a>incremental</a>
      <b>products and services</b>
      <c>radical</c>
      <d>life cycle maturation</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which type of change will have direct impact on the administrative domain in an organization?</q>
      <a>technology</a>
      <b>product and service</b>
      <c>strategy and structure</c>
      <d>people</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which type of change is strategic?</q>
      <a>changing domain</a>
      <b>installation of teams</b>
      <c>culture</c>
      <d>development of interorganizational relationships</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of Tom Kellys faces of innovation includes a hurdler, collaborator, and director?</q>
      <a>learning faces</a>
      <b>implementing faces</b>
      <c>building faces</c>
      <d>organizing faces</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which step of the change process involves coming up with a new way of doing things?</q>
      <a>need</a>
      <b>idea</b>
      <c>adoption</c>
      <d>resources</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>In attempting to make a change in his organization, Jake was happy to have a large number of people who were energetic and positive toward the change. Which essential element for successful change does this represent?</q>
      <a>adoption</a>
      <b>need</b>
      <c>resources</c>
      <d>competition</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Once decision makers choose to go ahead with a proposed idea, which of the following elements needed for a successful change occurs?</q>
      <a>need recognition</a>
      <b>adoption</b>
      <c>implementation</c>
      <d>resource acquisition</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following organizational type is flexible because of the freedom given to people to create and introduce new products?</q>
      <a>mechanistic</a>
      <b>bureaucratic</b>
      <c>organic</c>
      <d>resource</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is characteristic of the ambidextrous approach?</q>
      <a>using different structures and management processes for creation and for implementation</a>
      <b>introducing parts of a new procedure while maintaining parts of the old procedure</b>
      <c>design elements that are important for exploiting new ideas versus the design elements that are most suitable for exploring current capabilities</c>
      <d>highly skilled employees are used to implement change</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is the process used when organizations find creative ways to establish organic conditions for developing new ideas in the midst of more mechanistic conditions for implementing and using those ideas?</q>
      <a>culture change</a>
      <b>dual-core approach</b>
      <c>ambidextrous approach</c>
      <d>switching structures</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following provides a safe harbour where ideas from employees throughout the organization can be developed without interference from company bureaucracy or politics?</q>
      <a>creative departments</a>
      <b>idea incubator</b>
      <c>change champions</c>
      <d>venture teams</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following best describes how venture teams differ from other divisions within an organization?</q>
      <a>They may increase commitment, but they stifle creativity.</a>
      <b>They are often given a separate location and facilities.</b>
      <c>They are like a large company within a small company.</c>
      <d>They are most effective when used in a mechanistic organization.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Why is corporate entrepreneurship important for organizations looking to encourage innovation?</q>
      <a>It attempts to release the creative energy of all employees.</a>
      <b>It usually results in fewer, though higher-quality, innovations.</b>
      <c>It replaces creative departments and new venture teams.</c>
      <d>It results in idea champions who are the supervisors of production.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term refers to a separate, small, informal, highly autonomous, and often secretive group that focuses on breakthrough ideas for the business?</q>
      <a>idea champion</a>
      <b>idea incubator</b>
      <c>new-venture fund</c>
      <d>skunkworks</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>According to a survey mentioned in the textbook, what percentage of all new products achieved economic success? 3 percent, 12 percent, 30 percent, 60 percent?</q>
      <a>3 percent</a>
      <b>12 percent</b>
      <c>30 percent</c>
      <d>60 percent</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following was discovered in the study called Project SAPPHO?</q>
      <a>Successful innovating companies made more effective use of technology developed in-house and did more work in-house.</a>
      <b>Successful innovating companies had a much better understanding of operations and paid less attention to marketing.</b>
      <c>Employees in successful innovating companies had little say in the way production processes were developed or in decision making.</c>
      <d>Companies that were the most successful innovators were those where top management support was from people who had greater authority.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>According to Project SAPPHO, which of the following approaches is most likely to make new products more successful?</q>
      <a>A company pays more attention to production than to marketing so quality can improve.</a>
      <b>Outside technology is used.</b>
      <c>Most work is done by subcontractors.</c>
      <d>Those without much authority or seniority become product champions.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What are the key components of organizational design that contribute to successful new product innovation?</q>
      <a>specialization, boundary spanning, and horizontal coordination</a>
      <b>formalization, hierarchy, and organic structure</b>
      <c>specialization, formalization, and standardization</c>
      <d>dual-core processes, top management support, and incremental change</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following refers to excellent linkages between each department involved with new products and with relevant sectors in the external environment?</q>
      <a>specialization</a>
      <b>boundary spanning</b>
      <c>horizontal communication</c>
      <d>coordination</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What term is used for delivering products and services faster than competitors?</q>
      <a>competitive advantage</a>
      <b>horizontal linkages</b>
      <c>time-based competition</c>
      <d>boundary spanning</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following suggests that many organizations must adopt frequent administrative changes and need to be structured differently from those that rely on frequent technical and product changes for competitive advantages?</q>
      <a>horizontal linkage model</a>
      <b>switching structure</b>
      <c>ambidextrous approach</c>
      <d>dual-core approach</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which force for culture change relates to breaking down boundaries both within and between companies to create companies that are focused on knowledge sharing?</q>
      <a>the learning organization</a>
      <b>diversity</b>
      <c>large group intervention</c>
      <d>re-engineering and horizontal organizing</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Organizational development often entails large group intervention that involves which of the following?</q>
      <a>radical or transformational change in organizations</a>
      <b>electronic data interchange for the organization as a whole</b>
      <c>teaching hourly and salaried workers how to participate in strategic planning</c>
      <d>attempts to bring new emphasis to total quality management</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which term refers to the intervention technique used when an organizational development consultant brings together a group to discuss and solve problems involving conflicts, goals, decision making, or communication?</q>
      <a>survey feedback</a>
      <b>team building</b>
      <c>culture management</c>
      <d>technical training</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>As a change agent, Tommy has ensured that there has been constant communication with his employees to make sure they know what is going on and understand how it affects their jobs. Which organizational barrier to change is he trying to remove?</q>
      <a>uncertainty avoidance</a>
      <b>fear of loss</b>
      <c>risk that is too low</c>
      <d>excessive focus on costs</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
  </chapter>
  <chapter num="ch_12.text.fix">
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following are wicked problems associated with?</q>
      <a>conflicts over objectives and alternatives</a>
      <b>the garbage can model</b>
      <c>intuitive decision making</c>
      <d>problem consensus</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which type of decision making would typically be used, to the extent possible, in an objective process of selecting a new employee?</q>
      <a>inspiration and imitation</a>
      <b>the Carnegie model</b>
      <c>the garbage can model</c>
      <d>the rational approach</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>When Tanya Smith, CEO of Food Lion, reads Modern Grocer, visits other grocery stores to compare prices, and reviews daily sales figures, which step of the rational approach is she is engaging in?</q>
      <a>monitoring the decision environment</a>
      <b>defining the decision problem</b>
      <c>specifying decision objectives</c>
      <d>diagnosing the problem</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is the last step in the rational approach to decision making?</q>
      <a>defining the decision problem</a>
      <b>evaluating alternatives</b>
      <c>implementing the chosen alternative</c>
      <d>diagnosing the problem</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which step in the rational approach immediately follows developing alternative solutions?</q>
      <a>evaluating alternatives</a>
      <b>diagnosing the problem</b>
      <c>implementing an alternative to test its viability</c>
      <d>implementing the chosen alternative</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is the stage in which alternative courses of action are considered and one is chosen and implemented?</q>
      <a>the first three steps of the rational approach, called problem recognition</a>
      <b>the last four steps of the rational approach, called problem solution</b>
      <c>programmed decision</c>
      <d>bounded rationality</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What are the first four steps of the rational approach to decision making specifically designed to help a manager do?</q>
      <a>follow the scientific method</a>
      <b>devise a problem solution</b>
      <c>evaluate alternative solutions</c>
      <d>identify the problem</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is the best description of bounded rationality?</q>
      <a>It is a rational decision-making framework for managers.</a>
      <b>It is an eight-step decision-making process, including both problem identification and problem solution.</b>
      <c>It is a way to quantify data enabling decision-makers to gain the time to weigh all alternatives correctly.</c>
      <d>It is how decisions have to be made under severe time and resource constraints.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is recognized as a constraint and tradeoff during nonprogrammed decision making?</q>
      <a>personal constraints</a>
      <b>environmental constraints</b>
      <c>rationality constraints</c>
      <d>operational constraints</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What do managers employ when using intuitive decision making?</q>
      <a>logic</a>
      <b>judgment</b>
      <c>explicit reasoning</c>
      <d>a systematic approach</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following describes when intuitive decision-making processes work best?</q>
      <a>when managers can use networked computer databanks for analysis</a>
      <b>when there are few alternatives available</b>
      <c>when experience with similar decisions is extensive, and has been successful</c>
      <d>when a manager must make the decision alone</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>In the Paramount Pictures example in the textbook, what style of decision making did Sherry Lansing use in selecting films to make?</q>
      <a>intuitive</a>
      <b>high-velocity escalation</b>
      <c>marketing research, comparable to the rational approach</c>
      <d>scientific management</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>When is it best to use the management science model for decision making?</q>
      <a>when problems are unanalyzable, and problem consensus is high</a>
      <b>when problems are analyzable and measurable</b>
      <c>when solution knowledge is low, and problem consensus is low</c>
      <d>when solution knowledge is low, and problems cant be structured logically</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>When does management science work best for making decisions?</q>
      <a>when problems are vague</a>
      <b>when problems have unknown variables</b>
      <c>when problems are analyzable</c>
      <d>when problems are qualitative and cannot be quantified</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which type of organizational decision making is being used by a company that uses a computerized system extensively in its production process from the design stage through the automatic ordering of raw materials through preparation for delivery?</q>
      <a>garbage can</a>
      <b>incremental process</b>
      <c>Carnegie</c>
      <d>management science</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What does the Carnegie model of organizational decision making say about organizational decisions?</q>
      <a>that they involve few managers because of the simplicity with which decisions are made</a>
      <b>that they use coalitions for the final choice</b>
      <c>that they avoid the pitfalls of problemistic search</c>
      <d>that they use coalitions only at lower levels of management</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>A small university department included six faculty members. During faculty meetings when the department was faced with a difficult decision, a faculty member would suggest they take a break. During the break, four faculty members would adjourn to the coffee room and agree on the decision that would be made. What is this an example of?</q>
      <a>bounded rationality</a>
      <b>intuitive decision making</b>
      <c>a coalition</c>
      <d>crisis decision making</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>When the management team of an organization accepts a satisfactory rather than a maximum level of performance when making decisions, what are they engaging in?</q>
      <a>satisficing</a>
      <b>problemistic search</b>
      <c>problem consensus</c>
      <d>escalating commitment</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What does the incremental decision process model emphasize?</q>
      <a>political factors</a>
      <b>social factors</b>
      <c>the sequence of activities in the decision process</c>
      <d>intuitive processes</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which phase in the incremental decision process involves the shaping of a solution to an identified problem?</q>
      <a>development phase</a>
      <b>selection phase</b>
      <c>identification phase</c>
      <d>implementation phase</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following research results forms the basis of the incremental model?</q>
      <a>A manager with a proposal can get her idea implemented by breaking it down into small steps and installing one step before going on to another.</a>
      <b>Many major organizational decisions occur through a series of smaller decisions made over a fairly long period of time.</b>
      <c>Programmed decisions involve several mathematical formulas that build on each other.</c>
      <d>Algorithms are useful for prediction.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following are characteristics of organized anarchies?</q>
      <a>rapid change, unclear technology, and nonbureaucratic environment</a>
      <b>unclear technology, turnover, and problematic preferences</b>
      <c>problematic preferences, nonbureaucratic environment, and turnover</c>
      <d>rapid change, turnover, and unclear technology</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What does the garbage can model show?</q>
      <a>how poor inputs into decision making result in poor decisions</a>
      <b>how decisions can be made in mechanistic organizations</b>
      <c>four streams of events that influence decision making</c>
      <d>decision making in a stable environment</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is part of the garbage can model of decision making?</q>
      <a>A choice opportunity where the match up of problems and solutions result in decisions being made.</a>
      <b>Participants provide the stability needed to explain decision making, and remove its otherwise random quality.</b>
      <c>The company has an insufficient level of technology.</c>
      <d>Solutions and problems are tightly coupled.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is part of the garbage can model of decision making?</q>
      <a>Solutions may be proposed even when problems do not exist.</a>
      <b>Choices are not made unless problems are solved.</b>
      <c>Many problems are solved.</c>
      <d>No problem is allowed to persist without being solved.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What term is used for the agreement among managers about the nature of a problem or opportunity and about which goals and outcomes to pursue?</q>
      <a>organizational decision making</a>
      <b>problemistic search</b>
      <c>contingency decision making</c>
      <d>problem consensus</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>According to the contingency framework for decision models, when should the Carnegie Model for organizational decision making be used?</q>
      <a>when there is high uncertainty in both problems and solutions</a>
      <b>when managers agree on goals and look for optimal solutions</b>
      <c>when decisions are nonprogrammable and can be made by an individual</c>
      <d>in every cell of the framework</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Given the principles of escalating commitment, in which situation described below would you give the greatest funding to the same program in 2010?</q>
      <a>After you funded the program in 2008, it turned out to be very profitable.</a>
      <b>After another manager funded the program in 2008, it turned out to be very profitable.</b>
      <c>After you funded the program in 2008, it turned out to be a loser, showing actual prospects of failing.</c>
      <d>After another manager funded the program in 2008, it turned out to be a loser, showing actual prospects of failing.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following illustrates the phenomenon of escalating commitment?</q>
      <a>an increase in the commitment to a decision only when it begins to prove itself as correct or profitable</a>
      <b>continuing to invest time and money in a solution despite evidence of failure</b>
      <c>the need for top management to accept decisions made by lower levels and commit to their implementation</c>
      <d>incremental decision-making</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What process would explain increasing the budget for an ongoing project on which managers received feedback that it was destined for failure?</q>
      <a>the garbage can model</a>
      <b>flexible decision style</b>
      <c>escalating commitment</c>
      <d>organized anarchy</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
  </chapter>
  <chapter num="13">
    <question>
      <q>Which term is defined as the behaviour that occurs among organizational groups when participants identify with one group and perceive that other groups may block their groups goal achievement or expectations?</q>
      <a>goal incompatibility</a>
      <b>intergroup conflict</b>
      <c>political conflict</c>
      <d>strategic contingencies</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is probably the greatest cause of intergroup conflict in organizations?</q>
      <a>goal incompatibility</a>
      <b>differentiation</b>
      <c>task interdependence</c>
      <d>limited resources</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following attributes, that often generate intergroup conflict, relates to organizational departments with different outcome expectations?</q>
      <a>differentiation</a>
      <b>task interdependence</b>
      <c>goal incompatibility</c>
      <d>personality</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Putting together what you know about the sources of potential conflict and about interdependence, which of the following attributes will create the greatest potential for conflict?</q>
      <a>pooled interdependence</a>
      <b>functional interdependence</b>
      <c>reciprocal interdependence</c>
      <d>technology interdependence</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Applying what you know about sources of conflict, which of the following might you conclude would happen as task interdependence moves from pooled interdependence to reciprocal interdependence?</q>
      <a>Conflict would decrease and competition would increase.</a>
      <b>The potential for cooperation would increase.</b>
      <c>The potential for conflict would increase.</c>
      <d>Greater goal incompatibility would arise.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which organization model can managers use when goals are in alignment, there is little differentiation, departments are characterized by pooled interdependence, and resources seem abundant?</q>
      <a>a political model</a>
      <b>an open systems model</b>
      <c>an authoritarian model</c>
      <d>a rational model</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following denotes the ability of one person/department to influence other persons/departments to carry out orders or do something they would not otherwise have done?</q>
      <a>cooperation</a>
      <b>authority</b>
      <c>power</c>
      <d>personal position</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which type of power do managers enjoy because of their right to promote subordinates?</q>
      <a>legitimate</a>
      <b>reward</b>
      <c>coercive</c>
      <d>referent</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Where does legitimate power come from?</q>
      <a>the positions in the organization</a>
      <b>skill and knowledge</b>
      <c>personal characteristics</c>
      <d>resources controlled by managers</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Why do people have authority in an organization?</q>
      <a>because of the positions they hold</a>
      <b>because of skill and knowledge they possess</b>
      <c>because of personal characteristics</c>
      <d>because of resources they control</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which statement best describes how formal authority compares to power?</q>
      <a>Formal authority is more narrow in scope.</a>
      <b>Formal authority is the umbrella term that includes all power.</b>
      <c>Formal authority is the same as power.</c>
      <d>Formal authority is more dependent on personality.</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which statement best distinguishes power from authority?</q>
      <a>Power is vested in people.</a>
      <b>Power can be exercised upward, downward, and horizontally.</b>
      <c>Power flows down the vertical hierarchy.</c>
      <d>Power is more narrow in scope than authority.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a vertical source of power?</q>
      <a>control of limited resources</a>
      <b>network centrality</b>
      <c>formal authority</c>
      <d>manipulation</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What will happen if managers decide to control decision premises?</q>
      <a>They will tell subordinates the expected decision in advance.</a>
      <b>They will restrict the budget allocated to decision making.</b>
      <c>They will force subordinates to spend more time on decision making.</c>
      <d>They will place constraints on decisions made by lower-ranking persons.</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What term is used for being located in a part of the organization giving one access to information and people who are critical to the companys success?</q>
      <a>decision premises</a>
      <b>strategic contingencies</b>
      <c>network centrality</c>
      <d>power sources</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following best describes how network centrality relates to lower-level employees?</q>
      <a>It is out of reach because they cannot have access to critical information.</a>
      <b>It can be gained by becoming knowledgeable about certain activities or taking on difficult tasks and acquiring specialized knowledge.</b>
      <c>It makes no difference, because they cannot increase power.</c>
      <d>It takes on different meaning than it does for top managers; it means nothing more than being physically located next to those with power.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is difficult to measure because power differences are NOT defined on the organizational chart?</q>
      <a>a strategic contingency</a>
      <b>horizontal power</b>
      <c>dependency</c>
      <d>a decision premise</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What does the term strategic contingencies refer to?</q>
      <a>events and activities essential for attaining organizational goals</a>
      <b>environmental factors that have an indirect influence on goal attainment</b>
      <c>alternative strategic plans to cope with possible environmental changes</c>
      <d>competitors that may damage corporate standing</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which statement best describes what is known about horizontal power?</q>
      <a>It is reflected on the organizational flow chart.</a>
      <b>The sales department invariably carries a higher power rating than other departments.</b>
      <c>Its relationships change as strategic contingencies change.</c>
      <d>The concept of vertical linkages explains relative power.</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What is dependency power derived from?</q>
      <a>being dependent on others for something</a>
      <b>having something someone else wants</b>
      <c>becoming paternalistic in your management style</c>
      <d>immature subordinates</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is one measure of the extent to which the work of the department affects the final output of the organization?</q>
      <a>dependency</a>
      <b>financial resources</b>
      <c>nonsubstitutability</c>
      <d>centrality</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Fred tends to have a lot of power in his organization. He thinks it is because everyone likes him, whereas everyone else thinks it is because he is the only person who can make changes to the organizations software. What is the real basis for Freds power?</q>
      <a>coping with uncertainty</a>
      <b>financial resources</b>
      <c>dependency</c>
      <d>nonsubstitutability</d>
      <ans>D</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>What was uncovered by surveys of managers regarding what they think about political behaviour?</q>
      <a>Managers believe political behaviour is not common in organizations.</a>
      <b>Managers believe political behaviour arises when certain types of decisions need to be made, such as structural change, but is absent from other types, such as handling employee grievances.</b>
      <c>Most managers have a positive view of politics, and believe that it will more often help than hurt an organization in achieving its goals.</c>
      <d>Most managers think political behaviour occurs less often at upper rather than lower levels in organizations.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a mechanism for arriving at consensus when uncertainty is high and there is disagreement over goals or problem priorities?</q>
      <a>power</a>
      <b>authority</b>
      <c>politics</c>
      <d>decision premise</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a domain of political activity?</q>
      <a>management succession</a>
      <b>expanded networks</b>
      <c>resource dependence</c>
      <d>complex change</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a tactic to increase power?</q>
      <a>reducing dependencies</a>
      <b>satisfying strategic contingencies</b>
      <c>creating integrating devices</c>
      <d>increasing department size</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following is a political tactic for using power?</q>
      <a>expanding networks</a>
      <b>scheduling intergroup consultation</b>
      <c>creating integration devices</c>
      <d>satisfy strategic contingencies</d>
      <ans>A</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>When is confrontation as a method of reducing conflict likely to be more effective?</q>
      <a>when all other forms of collaboration have failed</a>
      <b>when no mutually acceptable outcomes can be envisioned</b>
      <c>when the conflict is viewed as a win-win situation and the groups avoid threats</c>
      <d>after a process of negotiation</d>
      <ans>C</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following best describes collective bargaining?</q>
      <a>It cannot be used to describe todays union-management relations, but does apply to general vertical conflict.</a>
      <b>It is one type of negotiation used to resolve disagreements between workers and management through a union, and establishes fixed responsibilities for the next two to three years.</b>
      <c>It is considered an integration device that results in contracts establishing flexible responsibilities for the next ten to fifteen years.</c>
      <d>It is considered on of the more innovative cooperative approaches.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
    <question>
      <q>Which of the following best describes the win-win strategy of negotiation?</q>
      <a>It avoids confrontation.</a>
      <b>It finds creative agreements that satisfy both groups.</b>
      <c>It encourages each group to pursue its own outcomes.</c>
      <d>It communicates a high commitment to your own position.</d>
      <ans>B</ans>
    </question>
  </chapter>
</testrepo>
